<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Filebase Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Thoughts, stories and ideas.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/</link><image><url>https://filebase.com/blog/favicon.png</url><title>Filebase Blog</title><link>https://filebase.com/blog/</link></image><generator>Ghost 3.39</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 17:31:26 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://filebase.com/blog/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[IPFS: Publishing To The DHT]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Distributed Hash Table (DHT) is a method of mapping keys to their associated values. They are fundamentally databases of keys and value pairs that are split across all the peers on a distributed network. ]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-publishing-to-the-dht/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6356d817a51e73009dd71670</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[DHT]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 18:38:28 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/dht.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/dht.png" alt="IPFS: Publishing To The DHT"><p>As InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) gains more popularity and adoption across the Web3 space, it’s quickly becoming the default storage method for the decentralized web. This increased growth of IPFS can be attributed to the protocol’s simple yet powerful functionality features: data publicity and content addressing. </p><p>Like many Web3 tools and infrastructure, understanding the technology’s inner- workings behind the scenes is vital to properly utilizing the tool and making proper decisions regarding your personal use case. </p><p>At the fundamental level, IPFS is a decentralized peer-to-peer file storage protocol. It isn’t inherently a decentralized storage network like Filecoin or Sia. IPFS uses two technologies on the backend that set it apart from other decentralized file storage solutions: Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAGs) and Distributed Hash Tables (DHTs).</p><h2 id="what-is-a-directed-acyclic-graph-dag-">What is a Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG)?</h2><p>Directed Acyclic Graphs (DAG) are data structures created when a file is uploaded to IPFS. A graph is a method used to showcase objects and the relationship between them. A directed graph is when a graph’s edges have direction; an acyclic graph is a graph that's edges have definitive ends and do not create a loop to other objects. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/pZ47cq_aoy3C8k-YEiH-qGHx0-Xkf7SsDW-Ju-D_9zjY6PaHt_TzW9UWr-AdXO1jQv4qDGy37EM2JqLOt9y2oS7lOUAkqp7Gnz5_cKWrkK1RSLwp3my3G7o7vrAWwzU0ukQriJ-e5mJz7-YVJ3Lv7QK7p3NAd3hDc1y630bs7HNfA9xYiYB-zuR2Ew" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Publishing To The DHT"></figure><p>IPFS uses a type of DAG known as a Merkle DAG. Merkle DAGs allow for nodes to have multiple parent nodes, providing functionality for chunk de-duplication. De-duplication means that when the duplicated content is stored on the network, it does not need to be stored and transmitted more than once. This helps save on the network's storage and bandwidth resources. Merkle DAGs are agnostic regarding content’s storage location and are not required to be updated when a file is replicated or removed.</p><h2 id="what-is-a-distributed-hash-table-dht-">What is a Distributed Hash Table (DHT)?</h2><p>A Distributed Hash Table (DHT) is a method of mapping keys to their associated values. They are fundamentally databases of keys and value pairs that are split across all the peers on a distributed network. </p><p>In order to upload or retrieve data stored on IPFS, there must be a mapping of each node’s PeerID and the content identifiers (CIDs) that the peer is storing. The DHT maintains this mapping of each CID with the PeerID of the nodes that are hosting that specific CID. </p><p>When a new peer joins the network, it can be classified in the DHT as either a DHT server or a DHT client. All of the DHT servers have public IP addresses that can be reached from the public Internet. In comparison, all DHT clients have private IP addresses that use protocols like Network Address Translation (NAT) to protect the privacy of the node. </p><p>When a new peer joins the network, it is a DHT client by default. This node then initiates connections with other peers on the network to begin participating. Once three or more peer nodes connect to a newly joined peer, the peer upgrades to act as a DHT server. DHT servers are capable of performing all functions on the network, like storing content or maintaining and serving CIDs and their associated PeerIDs when requested.</p><p>In comparison, DHT clients are only capable of requesting content from the network and do not store or provide content to other peers. This configuration is to avoid publicly unreachable peers being part of another peer’s routing table, which can cause issues within the file publication and retrieval process.</p><p>The flowchart below showcases how the IPFS content retrieval process works.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/hc-p60j2bb_6BLt11fsZoJxn954o20D-8QHYncCA_sjhXqDAwiRadXufxDlT3BjUkLO0t-B705JrlJdA0lS-1vf0oAsoTnl3tUB62nF3EWvT1DUnPkTdvf8ssZ6jKNGGrRCbVJU_KtMZlSe9XgMyrY-PUfvMx4TK3eiKLTigP8Ylg9NfXw2HukVtcw" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Publishing To The DHT"></figure><h2 id="why-does-publishing-to-the-dht-matter">Why Does Publishing to the DHT Matter?</h2><p>When content is uploaded to IPFS, its CID isn’t automatically published to the DHT servers. If you’re pinning content to IPFS through a personal IPFS node or an IPFS pinning service other than Filebase, your content isn’t benefiting from the best possible performance and content retrieval times. </p><p>As shown by the flowchart featured previously, if the CID isn’t found in the DHT, the request enters an idle looping state where it searches for CID providers consistently until a provider is found. Otherwise, the request times out, and the content isn’t retrieved. This is because some pinning service providers don’t publish their pinning provider records to the IPFS DHT servers. </p><p>By not publishing these records, the content retrieval process can take up to a minute, which is much longer compared to just a few seconds for content pinned to IPFS through Filebase. This is because Filebase publishes all of our provider records to IPFS DHT servers for the best performance and fastest retrieval time possible when a CID is requested.</p><h2 id="filebase-geo-redundant-ipfs-pinning">Filebase: Geo-redundant IPFS Pinning</h2><p>When content is uploaded to an IPFS bucket on Filebase, its CID is published to the IPFS DHT servers, along with being pinned with 3 copies stored across 3 unique geographic locations in the United States, London, and Frankfurt. </p><p>Through a combination of DHT publication and geo-redundant replication, CIDs hosted through Filebase are able to be retrieved at a fraction of the time compared to other IPFS pinning providers. </p><p>You can sign up for a <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord</a> server, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br><br><br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Announcing Automatic Bucket Migration for Skynet and Storj Customers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Filebase will be automatically migrating all existing Skynet and Storj buckets into Sia buckets.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/announcing-automatic-bucket-migration-for-skynet-and-storj-customers/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63515106a51e73009dd715ef</guid><category><![CDATA[Filebase]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 15:57:43 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/migration-1.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/migration-1.png" alt="Announcing Automatic Bucket Migration for Skynet and Storj Customers"><p>Today we're announcing automatic bucket migration for existing Skynet and Storj buckets. </p><p>Last month, <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/upcoming-changes-to-the-filebase-platform/">we announced</a> that we would be ending support for Skynet and Storj on our platform starting October 15th due to under utilization of these networks.</p><p>On October 15th, we disabled write operations for these networks to prevent uploads of new data, though read operations are still functional for users to manually migrate their data from Skynet and Storj buckets to a Sia or IPFS bucket. <em>Data stored in these buckets has not been removed. </em></p><p>To prevent data loss and aid in the migration process, Filebase will be <strong>automatically</strong> migrating all existing Skynet and Storj buckets into Sia buckets.</p><h3 id="what-does-this-mean-for-you">What Does This Mean For You?</h3><p>All URLs for objects stored in Skynet and Storj buckets will remain the same once they have been migrated to a Sia bucket. Bucket and object names will not be changed or altered. </p><p>There is no action required from the user's perspective, and current workflows or configurations using existing URLs will continue to function as they do now. </p><p>If you have any questions or concerns regarding this process, please email our team at: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 IPFS Use Cases You Haven't Thought Of Yet]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>IPFS is quickly emerging as the standard storage method for data in the Web3 ecosystem. Between the protocol’s distributed manner, content addressing format, and data publicity, IPFS allows for data to be uploaded and shared easily. Simply provide someone with the IPFS CID that was returned upon uploading the</p>]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/5-ipfs-use-cases-you-havent-thought-of-yet/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">634dccc3a51e73009dd715d0</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 14:28:54 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/five-IPFS.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/five-IPFS.png" alt="5 IPFS Use Cases You Haven't Thought Of Yet"><p>IPFS is quickly emerging as the standard storage method for data in the Web3 ecosystem. Between the protocol’s distributed manner, content addressing format, and data publicity, IPFS allows for data to be uploaded and shared easily. Simply provide someone with the IPFS CID that was returned upon uploading the file, and they can access that file from around the world without needing to log into an account or input any information. </p><p>Among the most common use-case of IPFS currently is the storage of NFT collection assets and their associated metadata files. The most popular of these collections include JPEG images, sometimes unique 1/1 images or other times randomly generated collections containing tens of thousands of individual pieces in a collection. </p><p>These JPEG files usually have a coordinating metadata file in the form of JSON that details the image’s attributes, such as its rarity in the collection, unique traits that provide perks like community access or in-game items, or any other configurable metadata field associated with the image. </p><p>Other common use cases of IPFS include hosting <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/decommerce">decentralized websites</a> or hosting <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/create-ipfs-app">decentralized applications</a>. IPFS supports uploading folders of multiple files, such as the files that make up a static website, which can then be hosted simply by uploading the folder to IPFS and accessing the folder’s CID through an IPFS HTTP gateway. <a href="https://ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs/QmTmMPDq7kyHk7BvRGr3JdfMQZNBy3HPKmX2tFxJK3pVZP/">Here’s an example of a static webpage hosted on IPFS. </a></p><p>While these are the most popular uses of IPFS currently, they barely scrape the surface of what IPFS can be used for. Here are 5 uses cases of IPFS that you haven’t thought of yet.</p><h2 id="1-distributed-package-management">1. Distributed Package Management</h2><p>Package managers, like NPM, are typically stored and managed in a centralized manner. By hosting software packages on IPFS, they can be stored in a distributed manner that is publicly available. Any changes to the package’s versions, like a bug fix, will be reflected by a new CID value, allowing for verification of updates and tracking package development.</p><h2 id="2-hosting-software-containers">2. Hosting Software Containers</h2><p>Software containers, like Docker containers, are available through registries like the Docker registry. This is similar to pulling a package from NPM, but for software containers rather than packages. By using IPFS to host your own registry, there isn’t any domain hosting configuration, DNS management, or user permission management. Simply use the IPFS CID with an IPFS HTTP gateway inside a curl command rather than use a docker pull command to download the container’s image.</p><h2 id="3-decentralized-ecommerce-websites">3. Decentralized eCommerce websites</h2><p>Through packages like <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/decommerce">DeCommerce</a>, spinning up your own eCommerce website is as simple as uploading the DeCommerce folder to your Filebase bucket, then navigating to the IPFS HTTP gateway URL of your folder’s CID. Since you’re equipped with all the necessary webpages and configurations, you can spend time customizing the CSS files to style your website and upload your products, rather than spending time managing a domain, SSL certificates, or figuring out how to accept crypto payments (which DeCommerce comes equipped with by default!).</p><h2 id="4-decentralized-operating-systems">4. Decentralized Operating Systems</h2><p>Along with decentralized software packages and containers, decentralized operating systems are another form of software that can benefit from being hosted on IPFS. A handful of decentralized, blockchain-based operating systems have emerged, but storing the data for these operating systems on their native blockchain is typically against best practices since it can be expensive and have high latency. For this reason, many layer-1 blockchains will either store data externally, like on IPFS, or they’ll use a layer-2 chain to handle data storage. Therefore, decentralized operating systems that run on a blockchain can highly benefit from being hosted on IPFS while they communicate externally with the blockchain network.</p><h2 id="5-decentralized-peer-reviews-of-academic-research-papers">5. Decentralized Peer Reviews of Academic Research Papers</h2><p>In addition to JPEG art being minted as NFT collections, pieces of writing such as blog posts, eBooks, and whitepapers have begun to gain traction as NFTs as well. Written content benefits from being minted on a blockchain since it verifies who the original writer of the content is, allowing for easier clarification when it comes to copyright, plagiarism, or other duplication of writing. Any text document or Microsoft Word document can be hosted on IPFS and then referenced inside of a smart contract that is deployed on Ethereum or Polygon, creating a permanent record of that piece of writing being created by the author. </p><p>For academic papers, this is a real game changer. Users can mint their research papers as an NFT that uses PDF or text documents hosted on IPFS, and then gain a verifiable reputation for their research and any peer reviews they contribute to other researchers. In addition to the smart contract’s verifiable address, the IPFS CID can be used as an additional form of verification that the content was created by the original author and hasn’t been altered since publication.</p><h2 id="filebase-geo-redundant-ipfs-pinning">Filebase: Geo-redundant IPFS Pinning</h2><p>To properly benefit from any of these use cases, though, the files and folders you upload to IPFS must be pinned. If data isn’t pinned to IPFS, it isn’t stored long-term. By default, data uploaded to the IPFS network is only stored in a node’s cache storage. To maintain the resources on the network, an automatic process known as the garbage collection process occurs. This process clears the cache storage of nodes to maintain their local resources. If you use IPFS for anything other than temporary storage, like any of the use cases listed above, unpinned data will break your entire workflow. </p><p>By default, all files and folders uploaded to an IPFS bucket on Filebase are pinned with 3 copies stored across 3 unique geographic locations in the United States, London, and Frankfurt. Using this infrastructure, 2 out of the 3 IPFS nodes can be inaccessible or down due to an outage, maintenance, or other reason, and the file will still be accessible. </p><p>Redundancy and accessibility are especially important for hosting software, websites, and assets, which rely on reliable infrastructure for users to make purchases, download packages, or view NFTs. </p><p>You can sign up for a <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[IPFS in the Metaverse]]></title><description><![CDATA[For Web3 communities, using metaverse platforms is often one of the most beneficial ways for community members to interact with each other in a manner that can resemble meeting in real life at a restaurant, event expo, or industry conference. ]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-in-the-metaverse/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6345bcf4a51e73009dd715b9</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 18:35:19 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/Metaverse.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/Metaverse.png" alt="IPFS in the Metaverse"><p>The term ‘metaverse’ can refer to any digital or virtual reality platform that combines any combination of aspects from online gaming, social media, virtual reality, augmented reality, cryptocurrencies, or NFTs for users to interact with one another. Metaverse worlds aren’t necessarily a uniquely Web3 aspect, though Web3 technologies are being used to develop existing Metaverse platforms further or develop entirely Web3-based metaverse worlds. </p><p>For example, the online gaming platform Roblox is considered to be a metaverse world, though it doesn’t use cryptocurrency, NFTs, or blockchain technology on the platform. In contrast, the virtual world Decentraland is an entirely Web3-based platform that utilizes NFTs, cryptocurrencies, decentralized storage, and blockchain networks on the backend.</p><h2 id="web3-s-metaverse-foothold">Web3’s Metaverse Foothold</h2><p>For Web3 communities, using metaverse platforms is often one of the most beneficial ways for community members to interact with each other in a manner that can resemble meeting in real life at a restaurant, event expo, or industry conference. </p><p>In addition to this, Web3-native metaverse worlds benefit from the unique use cases of token-gating through the use of NFTs, allowing for the capability of private virtual worlds or exclusive virtual items in these worlds. Creating a token-gated virtual community has become an attractive benefit of many NFT collections and communities, such as Otherside, the virtual metaverse world created by Yuga Labs for the Bored Ape Yacht Club community.</p><p>The combination of these two attributes has given metaverse worlds a strong foothold in the Web3 space, despite not being a Web3-native concept.</p><h2 id="metaverses-and-ipfs">Metaverses and IPFS</h2><p>Each metaverse platform stores hundreds, even thousands, of terabytes of data. Everything from virtual graphics, world maps, in-game items such as buildings, real estate, vehicles, or other items, and each player’s character and their personal items must be stored somewhere. Typically, since many metaverse worlds use traditional Web2 infrastructure stacks, they use centralized storage like AWS or Google Cloud. Any outages of these storage providers result in the metaverse world being down and inaccessible for their users. </p><p>Web3-native metaverse platforms use decentralized storage options like Arweave or IPFS for storing assets used in the virtual reality world. IPFS is a decentralized peer-to-peer storage protocol that is used to facilitate the IPFS network. IPFS differs from decentralized storage networks in the aspect that other decentralized storage networks like Sia or Arweave are blockchain networks that rent node storage out in return for cryptocurrency. Additionally, data stored on decentralized storage networks are typically private, unlike IPFS, where all data is publicly accessible through the content’s IPFS content identifier (CID) value.</p><h2 id="how-metaverses-benefit-from-ipfs">How Metaverses Benefit from IPFS</h2><h3 id="publicly-accessible">Publicly Accessible</h3><p>Since all content is publicly accessible through the file’s content identifier and an IPFS gateway URL, it’s easily integrated into metaverse platforms. There are no permissions to configure or manage and no complex pieces of code to download and then view the file.</p><h3 id="content-addressing">Content Addressing</h3><p>IPFS uses content addressing, where all content is accessed through a content identifier rather than a location address like HTTP uses. HTTP is susceptible to link rot, which is when a URL changes and makes content inaccessible since the URL is no longer valid. IPFS is not susceptible to link rot, since the CID of a file will never change and can always be accessed through the IPFS native URL or an IPFS gateway URL.</p><h3 id="support-for-all-content">Support For All Content</h3><p>IPFS supports uploading and hosting content of all forms, shapes, and sizes. Unlike some decentralized storage networks, there are no limitations for minimum or maximum file size, minimum or maximum data retention, or unsupported file types. IPFS can be used to store data in folders or as individual files, enabling a wide range of different workflows.</p><h2 id="filebase-geo-redundant-ipfs-pinning">Filebase: Geo-redundant IPFS Pinning</h2><p>When a file or folder is uploaded to IPFS, it must be pinned for it to persist on the network long term. Most pinning services use IPFS nodes on centralized providers like AWS or Azure, and only pin one copy of each file on one IPFS node in one geographic location.</p><p>By default, all files and folders uploaded to an IPFS bucket on Filebase are pinned with 3 copies stored across 3 unique, geographic locations in the United States, London, and Frankfurt. This way, 2 out of the 3 IPFS nodes can be inaccessible or down due to an outage, maintenance, or other reason, and the file will still be accessible. The Filebase geo-redundant IPFS pinning solution provides a reliable infrastructure for IPFS data to be stored.</p><p>Reliability and redundancy are especially important for metaverse worlds, which rely on consistent infrastructure uptime for the players in the virtual world. </p><p>You can sign up for a <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br><br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[IPFS: The Future of Content Distribution]]></title><description><![CDATA[The InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a communication protocol that facilitates data storage that uses content identification through content addressing. What does content addressing mean in terms of content distribution?]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-the-future-of-content-distribution/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">633b27b6a51e73009dd7157a</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 18:31:45 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/IPFS.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/IPFS.png" alt="IPFS: The Future of Content Distribution"><p>The InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a communication protocol that facilitates data storage that uses content identification through content addressing. What does content addressing mean in terms of content distribution?</p><h3 id="current-state-of-content-distribution">Current State of Content Distribution</h3><p>Imagine a scenario where you’re replying to an email and need to attach a word document. In your email client, attaching this document to the email is fairly straightforward. But now imagine that you want to share this same word document in a reply on Twitter. To share it this way, you’ll need to upload it to a file-sharing platform that can provide a sharing link. For others to view the word document, you’ll need to configure access for specific users through their email. If you intend to share this document with everyone who sees the post on Twitter, you’ll have to add each user’s email address manually every time someone wants to view the document. <br><br>This process can be complicated and prevent users from sharing files other than things like JPEG images that can be easily attached to posts on social media or similar types of websites. It doesn’t include the distribution of more complex files and libraries, like software packages, virtual games, or the source code of websites. What if you want to share this content with an easy link that doesn’t require authentication to download the files?</p><p>The method described above showcases the problems of content distribution that currently uses location addressing. Location addressing is used by protocols like HTTP/HTTPS, and refers to retrieving stored documents or files based on their location on a web server. Locations are typically referred to using the file’s URL, which follows a format similar to:</p><blockquote><a href="https://filebase.com/blog/how-decentralized-finance-uses-ipfs-and-why/">https://filebase.com/blog/how-decentralized-finance-uses-ipfs-and-why/</a></blockquote><p>In comparison, IPFS uses content addressing. Each file uploaded to IPFS is given a unique content identifier that is generated using the file or folder’s cryptographic hash value. Additionally, every file or folder uploaded to IPFS is publicly accessible using this CID. This means that any file can be shared using the CID and an IPFS gateway URL, without having to maintain sharing permissions. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/image--1-.png" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: The Future of Content Distribution" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/10/image--1-.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/10/image--1-.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/image--1-.png 1145w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>The best part? IPFS links never change or expire if the file is pinned to the IPFS network. </p><p>Want to learn more about IPFS pinning’s importance, and Filebase’s geo-redundant IPFS pinning service? <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-why-does-pinning-matter-anyway/">Check out this blog post. </a></p><p>Typically, URLs will change or expire when the location of the file changes on the web server that’s hosting it. A single change in the URL can make the link break, resulting in a short longevity for content to be accessed through location addressing methods. IPFS CIDs will never change - any change to a file requires that the file be re-uploaded to IPFS and it will be given an entirely new, unique CID. Through this workflow, you can share anything Twitter simply by inserting the IPFS gateway and CID into the post.</p><p>How can IPFS be used for distributing different types of content?</p><h3 id="distributing-written-content">Distributing Written Content</h3><p>IPFS is a great method of distributing written content, such as blog posts or documentation. IPFS can be used to host static blog websites, simply by uploading the blog’s HTML files as a folder to IPFS. The IPFS CID of the folder can be accessed through an IPFS gateway which will then display the website without any additional configuration or setup. This is a good solution for users who want to jump start their Web3 blog, especially since it showcases using the IPFS decentralized storage technology. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/IPFS-Doc-Images.png" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: The Future of Content Distribution" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/10/IPFS-Doc-Images.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/10/IPFS-Doc-Images.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/10/IPFS-Doc-Images.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/10/IPFS-Doc-Images.png 2080w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Written content can also be minted as an NFT. When an NFT is minted onto a network, the NFT’s assets must be stored somewhere. IPFS is a popular solution for this, since CIDs do not expire and are publicly accessible. Pieces of writing can be stored on IPFS, then referred to in an NFT smart contract to be minted on a blockchain network.</p><h3 id="art-distribution">Art Distribution</h3><p>NFTs are one of the most popular uses of IPFS, since NFT collections benefit from storing assets off-chain on platforms like IPFS. Storing hundreds of thousands of image files and their associated metadata JSON files on-chain is expensive and inefficient. For a seamless solution that uses Web3 technologies, IPFS is often the answer. To avoid rug pulls of collections, though, assets must be pinned on IPFS to prevent them from being removed during the automatic <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/ipfs/ipfs-pinning#understanding-the-garbage-collection-process">IPFS garbage collection</a> process.</p><h3 id="distributing-software-and-virtual-games">Distributing Software and Virtual Games</h3><p>Distributing software packages using IPFS is relatively new but groundbreaking application of IPFS. One platform that is doing an incredible job of facilitating software and game deployment and distribution is <a href="https://www.valist.io/">Valist.</a> Apps can be published on Valist without paying gas or distribution fees, and all monetization for software is done through Software License NFTs deployed on the Polygon network. Each piece of software uploaded to Valist is automatically pinned to Filebase on the backend, resulting in geo-redundant and reliable software distribution and storage.</p><p>Want to get started using IPFS to distribute content yourself?<br><br>You can sign up for a <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">free Filebase account to get started</a> with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br><br><br><br><br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Building DeFi with IPFS]]></title><description><![CDATA[For DeFi to truly be decentralized, it needs to use decentralized storage. Storing data on a centralized provider, like AWS, doesn’t support the DeFi attributes of transparency and decentralization.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/how-decentralized-finance-uses-ipfs-and-why/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6331fd9fa51e73009dd71505</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[DeFi]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 20:28:31 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/Defi.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/Defi.png" alt="Building DeFi with IPFS"><p>Decentralized finance, commonly known as DeFi, is a financial technology that uses decentralized, distributed ledgers known as blockchains to verify and execute transactions without using a financial intermediary. </p><p>DeFi refers to any transaction or exchange that utilizes cryptocurrencies and tokens. Examples of DeFi include decentralized cryptocurrency exchanges, digital asset marketplaces for assets like NFTs, and decentralized eCommerce websites. </p><p>DeFi removes third-party, centralized institutions from financial transactions to provide widespread access to banking and financial accounts without paying transaction fees or requiring extensive documentation to open an account. This way, DeFi is able to provide financial freedom to individuals located in third-world countries without access to traditional institutions. It also provides a censorship-resistant alternative to traditional banking solutions. While DeFi might sound insecure or unreliable, it's actually highly secure and incredibly reliable, thanks to blockchain networks. </p><h3 id="how-defi-works">How DeFi Works</h3><p>DeFi uses blockchain networks to validate and execute transactions. When a transaction is submitted to a DeFi platform, whether it be a decentralized exchange or a simple transfer between wallets, the transaction is submitted to the blockchain's network of nodes. Blockchains use a pool of validator nodes to achieve network consensus, a process which verifies that the submitted transaction is valid and legitimate. Once validated, the transaction is recorded into a block along with other transactions and a record of the block that came before it. This creates a chain of blocks that are linked together, since each block contains info about the block directly before it. </p><p>Blockchains are permanent, immutable ledgers. Once a block has been written to the chain, it cannot be removed or changed. If blockchains were mutable, they wouldn’t be able to be trusted for executing financial transactions without a center intermediary. Only due to their immutable nature have they been able to facilitate DeFi functionality.</p><h3 id="benefits-of-defi">Benefits of DeFi</h3><p>DeFi has gained widespread traction across the globe not only due to its immutable nature but for other important reasons such as:</p><ul><li><strong>Accessibility</strong>: Creating a crypto wallet to send and receive crypto payments is a form of DeFi, and can be done by anyone without needing to verify your identity, make a deposit, or pay a fee.</li><li><strong>Low fees</strong>: DeFi transactions have low transaction fees compared to traditional centralized finance, and investing in various DeFi technologies like liquidity pools.</li><li><strong>Transparency</strong>: The record of all transactions on a blockchain network is publicly accessible, providing a level of transparency that can be verified by anyone.</li><li><strong>Autonomy</strong>: DeFi platforms don’t rely on centralized middlemen to approve transactions, and aren’t subjected to risks that traditional financial intermediaries are, like bankruptcy or adversity.</li></ul><h3 id="who-uses-defi">Who Uses DeFi?</h3><p>The beauty of DeFi is that it can be used by anyone in the world. Creating a crypto wallet and connecting it to a DeFi app or platform can be achieved by anyone. Currently, the most common users of DeFi include:</p><ul><li>NFT collectors and creators.</li><li>Cryptocurrency investors.</li><li>Personnel who don’t have access to traditional banking solutions.</li></ul><h3 id="how-does-defi-use-ipfs">How Does DeFi Use IPFS?</h3><p>For DeFi to truly be decentralized, it needs to use decentralized storage. Storing data on a centralized provider, like AWS, doesn’t support the DeFi attributes of transparency and decentralization. Data stored on centralized storage providers can be used for advertising or other unsolicited purposes, and is susceptible to outages due to its several single points of failure.</p><p><a href="https://ipfs.io/">IPFS</a>, or InterPlanetary File System, is a decentralized communication protocol that is used to facilitate the functionality of the IPFS network. Through the IPFS protocol, nodes around the world are connected to a decentralized peer-to-peer network that is used for file storage. This form of file storage uses content addressing, which is a manner of file retrieval that uses a content identifier rather than the file’s location on a web server. </p><p>IPFS is a popular solution for DeFi applications to store or host data, since all data stored on IPFS can be accessed publicly through the file’s content identifier, and things like <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/build-using-ipfs-not-https/">link rot</a> aren’t a concern. This provides a reliable and persistent data storage solution that isn't susceptible to outages due to the network's decentralized nature. </p><p>While it’s clear that DeFi uses decentralized blockchain peer-to-peer networks for transaction execution, how can DeFi utilize IPFS today?</p><ul><li>Decentralized eCommerce platforms can store product listing information like images, metadata, and transaction history off-chain on IPFS to minimize the amount of data they store on blockchains like Ethereum or Polygon.</li><li>Digital asset collections like NFT collections often use IPFS to store NFT images and their associated metadata files.</li><li>Decentralized applications that serve a decentralized finance function like a decentralized exchange app can be stored and deployed on IPFS, then accessed in a web browser using the application’s content identifier and an IPFS gateway.</li><li>Decentralized exchanges can store a record of their transaction history on IPFS as a secondary backup of all actions on their platform that can be easily referenced or parsed through.</li><li>Decentralized autonomous organization (DAO) voting and governance can use IPFS to store organization change proposals, such as how to distribute and spend DAO treasury funds. All votes for the proposal can be persisted off-chain on IPFS instead of being stored on-chain.</li></ul><h3 id="building-defi-with-ipfs-on-filebase">Building DeFi with IPFS on Filebase</h3><p><a href="https://filebase.com/">Filebase</a> is a decentralized storage and geo-redundant IPFS pinning service. All files stored in an IPFS bucket on Filebase are <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-why-does-pinning-matter-anyway/">pinned</a> to the network with 3x redundancy across diverse geographic locations in the United States, London, and Germany. The term ‘pinning’ refers to storing data on an IPFS node for long-term data persistence that isn’t at risk of being removed by the automatic resource allocation process known as <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/ipfs/ipfs-pinning#understanding-the-garbage-collection-process">IPFS garbage collection</a>.<br><br>A few use-cases of using DeFi with IPFS on Filebase include:</p><ul><li><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/decommerce">Creating a decentralized ecommerce website with DeCommerce that’s hosted on IPFS.</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/alchemy/alchemy-build-a-dapp-that-provides-real-time-ethereum-transaction-notifications">Building a decentralized app that tracks Ethereum transactions for your crypto wallet.</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/agoric/agoric-create-a-defi-dapp-using-agoric-thats-stored-on-filebase">Creating a DeFi app on the Agoric network.</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials/thirdweb/thirdweb-create-an-nft-marketplace-with-thirdweb-and-ipfs">Deploying an NFT marketplace app with thirdweb and Filebase.</a></li></ul><p>You can <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">sign up for a free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br><br><br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?]]></title><description><![CDATA[When a file is stored on an IPFS node, it is stored in the node’s cache storage unless it is ‘pinned’. When a file is pinned on an IPFS node, it is stored in the node’s permanent storage, for long-term, persistent availability. ]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/ipfs-why-does-pinning-matter-anyway/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6329dcf116cf2a009d015d67</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 14:30:06 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/Pinning.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/Pinning.png" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?"><p>When you hear the term ‘pinning’, what do you think of? Some people might think about a cork board that they pin photographs and other paper items onto in a collage format, while others might think about putting a decorative pin into a hat or jacket. The intent, however, is the same - whatever you are pinning, you want it to persist in the location you pinned it to in order for it to serve a purpose.</p><h2 id="what-is-pinning">What is Pinning?</h2><p>Pinning, in regards to IPFS, is similar to the idea of pinning a photo onto a cork board. </p><p>The InterPlanetary File System, or IPFS, is a decentralized peer-to-peer protocol that enables nodes to store and transfer files between one another. IPFS isn’t inherently a network itself - it's a communication protocol that outlines the workflow and components that enable the IPFS network to exist. Software like the IPFS daemon and IPFS desktop provide nodes the ability to participate in and interact with other nodes running the same software, thus creating a network of peers storing and sharing files between themselves. </p><p>When a file is stored on an IPFS node, it is stored in the node’s cache storage unless it is ‘pinned’. When a file is pinned on an IPFS node, it is stored in the node’s permanent storage, for long-term, persistent availability. Think of it like pinning a photo onto a cork board. The photo will remain on the cork board until you remove the pin. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image-1.png" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/09/image-1.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image-1.png 750w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><h2 id="why-files-need-to-be-pinned">Why Files Need To Be Pinned</h2><p>If a file on an IPFS node isn’t pinned and remains in the node’s cache storage, the file will be removed during the next run of the automatic IPFS garbage collection process. Garbage collection is an automated process that frees up used resources on IPFS nodes to make space for new files to be stored in the node’s cache storage.</p><p>IPFS pinning is important if the file you upload needs to be accessible for a long period of time. It’s difficult to determine how long a file will be persistent on the IPFS network when it’s not pinned since while it can exist in one node’s cache storage, it can also exist in the cache storage of other nodes if those nodes have recently retrieved the file from the original node that was storing it. The garbage collection process might run at different times across these nodes, so while the original node might not store the file anymore, it might still be cached on another node or several other nodes. </p><p>Pinning ensures that no matter how many nodes have the file cached, it will always be available on at least one node. Most pinning providers only pin files on one IPFS node, which creates a single point of failure. If this single node goes offline, so do the files that it is pinning. While the files might be cached on other nodes, there is no guarantee that they are. </p><p>When a file is uploaded to a Filebase IPFS bucket, it is automatically pinned onto the IPFS network with copies stored on 3 different nodes across 3 diverse geographic locations in the United States, London, and Germany. This creates automatic 3x redundancy for all files pinned to IPFS through Filebase. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS3-Map.png" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/09/IPFS3-Map.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/09/IPFS3-Map.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/09/IPFS3-Map.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS3-Map.png 2050w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>By using Filebase for IPFS pinning, files aren’t at risk of being inaccessible due to a single point of failure. 2 of the 3 IPFS nodes pinning your file on the Filebase infrastructure could be offline, and your file would still be persisted on the network. This ensures that files maintain the highest level of reliability possible in comparison to other IPFS pinning services that only pin files once on a single node.</p><h2 id="pinning-content-to-ipfs-through-filebase">Pinning Content to IPFS Through Filebase</h2><p>To pin content to IPFS using Filebase, first, <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">sign up for a free Filebase account</a>. Then, log in to the <a href="https://console.filebase.com">web console dashboard</a>. </p><p>Create an IPFS Filebase bucket. Then select ‘Upload’ and select either ‘File’ or ‘Folder’ to pin a single file or a folder of multiple files to IPFS.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/ofGBhXD8s3weHUFhNCInQCsP3BgHD3IkOGJv3xAVKSZa27vf7tQSr3tOXLU6BWB6FXQDt3m_vARuluzKBwPbWFyklHGOi6Fm5Qti59aUmoxYZ-o2_jjv41sCWggOtLWlyT7ocI3rzUKhpv2ii1gE7TsII5dTMWL9O2115TeAHM-7jDmbxGIr7CopXA" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?"></figure><p>Filebase also supports re-pinning existing CIDs. This means you migrate from pinning files on your own local IPFS node, or from another pinning service provider, and pin those files to Filebase without having to re-upload the files. Simply select ‘Upload’ then ‘CID’, instead of file or folder.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-width-wide"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/j7b-qQRQWS3-kMFbmJEh6F3RDmb63AkyoYAgDJm9SVbNxW-kk3DEg948bRDYH-kZQ3vd41G27cBUUOw7R2h-tNesBm8IM1DQZlsfwMkyNDLLWkp3xhhoVKgG5JJgJpdFiEc7MEzKR8E82oKPausAaSPizBW9ookYWx-Ani60G1TtlcJQ74JlQ9iivA" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?"></figure><h2 id="ipfs-pin-sync">IPFS Pin Sync</h2><p>If you have hundreds or even thousands of IPFS CIDs that you want to migrate to Filebase and re-pin, it can be tedious and time-consuming to re-pin them one by one. That’s why we developed the IPFS Pin Sync tool, which synchronizes all pinned CIDs from one IPFS pinning service to Filebase. </p><p>Using IPFS Pin Sync is as easy as logging into the provider you’d like to migrate from, like Pinata, then logging into Filebase, and clicking ‘Sync’. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/4fyDaHHFck_fVz9vD0J3csv-thvzvIxtMKewMsTz564K4S0Tr3tTcRpm7wiUG864QgtJfBgWy8iF3V0T4iQc89d02QO0bhTymE6I_xTq0L7o_gH47ldASWjYYHt7DKKZYmAGnqCQ4PgjhRI0jnJTzR69zFk0OMz9eeICdDWOHJU6dJVYiTBQfcWu_Q" class="kg-image" alt="IPFS: Why Does Pinning Matter, Anyways?"></figure><p>The Filebase IPFS Pin Sync tool is available in-browser <a href="https://filebase.github.io/ipfs-pin-sync/">here</a>, and is free to use.</p><p>You can <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">sign up for a free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build On IPFS - Not HTTPS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Location addressing versus content addressing might be one of the biggest debates right now between the Web2 and Web3 ecosystems.  Here's why you should build on IPFS, not HTTPS.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/build-using-ipfs-not-https/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6329f97316cf2a009d015da0</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 18:53:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS.png" alt="Build On IPFS - Not HTTPS"><p>Location addressing versus content addressing might be one of the biggest debates right now between the Web2 and Web3 ecosystems.</p><h2 id="location-addressing-through-http-https">Location Addressing Through HTTP/HTTPS</h2><p>Web2, or the centralized internet, uses location addressing through the HTTP/HTTPS protocol to provide functionality for webpages to be routed to within a web browser. When a webpage is stored on a web server, it uses the HTTP/HTTPS protocol to serve that file as a public website that can be accessed around the globe. </p><p>When you navigate to a website, such as</p><blockquote>https://filebase.com/blog/heres-why-you-should-build-on-ipfs/</blockquote><p>you are navigating to a location where the article <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/heres-why-you-should-build-on-ipfs/">‘Here’s Why You Should Build On IPFS’</a> is located. This is because location addressing uses the location of the file within its hosting server. </p><p>For example, the blog post ‘Here’s Why You Should Build On IPFS’, is located on a web server that hosts the Filebase blog. If the blog post’s name portion of the URL, called a ‘slug’, changes or is moved, the link will no longer work and you will get an error page, like a 404 Not Found message. So if the title changes to ‘Here’s Why You Should Build On IPFS Today’, the link</p><blockquote> https://filebase.com/blog/heres-why-you-should-build-on-ipfs/ </blockquote><p>will no longer work.</p><h2 id="link-rot">Link Rot</h2><p>This disadvantage is referred to as ‘link rot’. It is one of the main disadvantages of using HTTP/HTTPS. Small changes to webpages or URL structures can cause entire webpages to be renamed and accessed at a new URL, causing updates to be required in any configurations that use those static URLs so that they reflect the new location of the content. </p><p>Several studies have been done to calculate how many URLs on the Internet are considered ‘dead’, or no longer accessible and return an error such as a 404 Not Found message. </p><p><a href="https://harvardlawreview.org/2014/03/perma-scoping-and-addressing-the-problem-of-link-and-reference-rot-in-legal-citations/">One study from 2014</a> of legal journals and other citations, found that about 70% of URLs originally cited in legal journals no longer existed, and around half of all URLs used by the United States Supreme Court for citing decisions no longer existed either. </p><p>Another study from 2012 estimated that of all social media links, about 30% would no longer exist in the next two years. </p><p>In a massive study completed by <a href="https://ahrefs.com/blog/link-rot-study/">Ahrefs.com that compiled data over a nine-year period</a>, they found that out of 174.3 million links, around 26.9 million were considered ‘dead’ or ‘lost’. Of these, the most common errors associated with links being inaccessible were caused by the links being dropped (47.7%), meaning in most cases the domain no longer exists entirely, or they were removed (34.2%), which means that the pages still exist, but the slug has changed so the original URL no longer works.</p><h2 id="content-addressing-through-ipfs">Content Addressing Through IPFS</h2><p><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/storage-networks/ipfs">InterPlanetary File System</a>, or IPFS, uses content addressing to reference stored content instead of location addressing. Content addressing means that all content stored using content addressing is referenced through the content’s identifier, or CID. </p><p>When a file is uploaded to IPFS, the file’s contents are used to generate a cryptographic hash value. This value is used to generate a second value, known as the file’s content identifier.</p><p>Two things are always true about IPFS CIDs:</p><ul><li>The same file or folder added to two separate IPFS nodes using the same settings and parameters will produce the same CID. Any difference in the content, such as metadata differences, will produce a different CID.</li><li>The length of the CID will be the same for every file or folder, regardless of the file size or content.</li></ul><p>CIDs can be used to reference that file using IPFS native links or IPFS HTTP gateways.</p><p>IPFS native links are in the form of:</p><blockquote>ipfs://[CID]</blockquote><p>IPFS HTTP gateways bridge the gap between the IPFS network and programs that don’t natively support IPFS. By using an IPFS HTTP gateway, CIDs can be accessed by anyone in the world through a web browser. IPFS HTTP gateways are in the form of:</p><blockquote>https://ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs/[CID]</blockquote><h2 id="content-addressing-isn-t-susceptible-to-link-rot">Content Addressing Isn’t Susceptible to Link Rot</h2><p>Content addressing doesn’t rely on URLs to remain the same or for domains to stay active. IPFS CIDs can be accessed through any IPFS HTTP gateway, with over a hundred public gateways to choose from currently.  As long as a CID is available on the IPFS network, the content can be accessed.</p><h2 id="ipfs-pinning">IPFS Pinning</h2><p>To assure that CIDs are always available on the network, they must be pinned to an IPFS node. IPFS pinning is the process of storing a file or folder on an IPFS node’s permanent storage, rather than the node’s cache storage. If a file isn’t pinned, it’s stored in cache storage that will be cleared periodically by the network’s garbage collection process. </p><p>Filebase is a geo-redundant IPFS pinning service, meaning each file uploaded to IPFS through Filebase is pinned with 3x replication across different diverse geographic locations. This 3x replication provides important redundancy and reliability that ensures CIDs are always accessible and available.</p><p>You can<a href="https://filebase.com/signup"> sign up for a free Filebase account</a> to get started with your IPFS journey today.</p><p>If you have any questions, please join our<a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx"> Discord server</a>, or send us an email at hello@filebase.com.<br><br><br><br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Upcoming changes to the Filebase platform]]></title><description><![CDATA[We're making big changes to the Filebase platform. Read on to learn more about what this means for you.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/upcoming-changes-to-the-filebase-platform/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">631f4a4116cf2a009d015c1c</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 18:56:21 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/February-Blog-Post-Images.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/February-Blog-Post-Images.png" alt="Upcoming changes to the Filebase platform"><p>Today we are writing to tell you about upcoming changes to the Filebase platform.</p><p>After much deliberation, we have decided that effective <strong>October 15th, 2022</strong>, we will be removing our Skynet and Storj integrations permanently. Users of these integrations will need to download all of their files prior to the date referenced above.</p><p><strong>Why are we making this change?</strong></p><p>During routine operation of our services, we regularly collect and review various usage metrics. We have ultimately determined that our Skynet and Storj integrations suffer from low usage. As a result, we have decided to permanently remove Skynet and Storj from our platform.</p><p><strong>Why now?</strong></p><p>Earlier this year, we released our IPFS integration. Since this release, the usage of this integration and the growth of our platform have both surged tremendously, overshadowing usage patterns from some of our other integrations entirely. This has caused us to place tremendous focus on IPFS in order to support the large influx of new IPFS users. As a startup company, we must follow where the traction takes us.</p><p>We want to offer the highest level of service possible to our customers. Moving forward, Sia and IPFS will be our primary focus.</p><p><strong>What does this mean for you?</strong></p><p>You will be able to stay on your current storage plan until <strong>October 15th, 2022</strong>.</p><p>After this date, the integrations referenced above will be removed and the data uploaded using them will be deleted.</p><p>As always, if you have any questions about these upcoming changes, please feel free to email our team at: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here's Why You Should Build On IPFS]]></title><description><![CDATA[When a Web3 developer begins building their project, they have a whole slew of questions that they need to answer to get started. One question is often an afterthought: Where will my project’s assets be stored? ]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/heres-why-you-should-build-on-ipfs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">630e3694ce5a82009d929527</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[Web3]]></category><category><![CDATA[interplanetary file system]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2022 15:53:33 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS_why.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/IPFS_why.png" alt="Here's Why You Should Build On IPFS"><p>When a Web3 developer begins building their project, they have a whole slew of questions that they need to answer to get started. </p><blockquote>What language do I want to write my smart contracts in? What will my project accomplish? What blockchains does it need to use? </blockquote><p>One question is often an afterthought: <em>Where will my project’s assets be stored? </em></p><p>For many, they start with local storage on their hard drive, then maybe they upload it to GitHub. Some will upload assets that they need to use in their app to a service like AWS, then reference it using an S3 URL. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image--7-.png" class="kg-image" alt="Here's Why You Should Build On IPFS" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/09/image--7-.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image--7-.png 619w"></figure><p>These workflows open several vulnerabilities. Local storage without any backup can be destroyed through data corruption or spilling coffee on your laptop. Centralized cloud providers have a single point of failure and come with restrictions like vendor lock-in or limitations regarding how your data can be accessed. GitHub is popular for maintaining code repositories, but for deploying a project to be live on the web, it's often not the best choice. <br><br>What if there was a better way to store both your project’s files and any assets that it uses that benefits from decentralization without a single point of failure, plus flexibility for any workflow? </p><h2 id="what-is-ipfs">What is IPFS?</h2><p>IPFS, or Interplanetary File System, is a decentralized content addressing protocol. When a file is uploaded to the IPFS network, it is given a unique identifier called a <a href="https://docs.ipfs.tech/concepts/content-addressing/">content identifier</a>, or CID. The CID is a record of the file’s existence on the network. When your file is requested to be viewed or downloaded, the nodes on the IPFS network communicate with one another to determine which node is storing the content referenced by the requested CID. </p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image--6-.png" class="kg-image" alt="Here's Why You Should Build On IPFS"></figure><p>When another node views or downloads the requested file, it is stored in the node’s cache data, creating another copy of the file within the network. The file will stay in the cache of the node until it is cleared through a process known as the IPFS garbage collection. </p><p>To keep files on the network indefinitely, they must pinned. Pinning is when a node on the IPFS network stores content without it being at risk of being deleted through the garbage collection process. </p><p>Since IPFS files and folders can be accessed through their CID, they can be referenced from anywhere in the world by anyone using an <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/storage-networks/ipfs/ipfs-gateways">IPFS gateway</a>. An IPFS gateway is dedicated to retrieving and serving content through a URL. This URL could be an IPFS URL like <em>ipfs:// </em>for programs or platforms that natively support IPFS, or this can be an HTTP URL like <em>ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs</em>. </p><p>By using content addressing, files on IPFS are:</p><ul><li>Available for anyone to view or download without authentication.</li><li>Available to be used by programs and platforms without restrictions.</li><li>Stored using a distributed network that is resilient to outages or disruptions. </li></ul><p>In addition to content addressing, all files uploaded to IPFS are <a href="https://docs.ipfs.tech/concepts/immutability/">immutable</a>. Once data is uploaded on IPFS, the file is immutable. If any changes are made to the file when it is re-uploaded, the CID generated for the file is different from the original. This is because when a file is uploaded, the CID is generated based on the cryptographic hash of the file. Any change to the file or its metadata will alter this cryptographic hash. </p><h2 id="filebase-geo-redundant-ipfs">Filebase: Geo-Redundant IPFS</h2><p>For a file to be truly decentralized and benefit from the persistence of the IPFS network, the IPFS pinning service must be announcing your data to the <a href="https://docs.ipfs.tech/concepts/dht/">DHT</a>, or distributed hash table. The DHT is responsible for mapping CIDs and their associated files across the network. If the IPFS pinning provider doesn’t announce to the DHT and the pinning provider’s node goes offline, so does your data.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image--8-.png" class="kg-image" alt="Here's Why You Should Build On IPFS" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/09/image--8-.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/09/image--8-.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/09/image--8-.png 1145w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p><a href="https://filebase.com">Filebase</a> is a geo-redundant IPFS pinning service that announces all data to the DHT. Every file and folder uploaded to the IPFS network through Filebase is automatically pinned to Filebase's IPFS infrastructure. Each pin is stored with a 3x level of redundancy, and each level is located in a different country and datacenter. The combination of DHT announcements and 3x redundancy provides a geo-redundant, reliable, and performant method of storing data on IPFS.</p><h2 id="what-can-i-build-on-ipfs">What can I build on IPFS?</h2><p>IPFS supports all file types, enabling hundreds of thousands of workflows. If you can think of it, you can build it. The most popular use-cases of IPFS currently include:</p><p><strong><a href="https://docs.alchemy.com/docs/how-to-develop-an-nft-smart-contract-erc721-with-alchemy">NFT Collections</a></strong>: NFT collections benefit from using IPFS CIDs to reference each NFT’s visual image file and its associated metadata file. </p><p><strong><a href="https://docs.unstoppabledomains.com/d-websites/connect-ipfs/">Decentralized Websites</a></strong>: IPFS supports hosting static websites through IPFS folders that contain the website’s assets and HTML files. These IPFS CIDs can be referenced throughout the world through IPFS gateways. Then, an IPFS gateway can be routed through a domain name like Unstoppable Domains. </p><p><strong><a href="https://medium.com/textileio/build-a-decentralized-chat-app-with-knockout-and-ipfs-fccf11e8ce7b">Decentralized Applications</a></strong>: dApps benefit from storing assets on IPFS, which can be referenced through their CID without having to reference or manage the files stored in the local development workspace. </p><p>Need some inspiration for your project? Check out these <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/web3-tutorials">Web3 tutorials</a> for ideas and workflows using IPFS on Filebase. </p><p>You can <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">sign up</a> for a free Filebase account to get started with your IPFS journey today. </p><p>If you have any questions, please join our <a href="https://discord.gg/rwXPs83Xsx">Discord server</a>, or send us an email at <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a>.<br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS]]></title><description><![CDATA[Read below to learn how to build an image gallery app with IPFS and Tailwind CSS using Filebase.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/build-an-image-gallery-app-with-ipfs-and-tailwind-css/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6250990b3af9d2009d1f75ac</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[Tailwind CSS]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 16:23:50 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/04/Copy-of-Docker.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/04/Copy-of-Docker.png" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"><p>Tailwind CSS is a utility-first CSS framework made for diverse yet simple website styling techniques.</p><p>In this tutorial, you will learn how to build an image gallery app with IPFS and Tailwind CSS using Filebase.</p><h3 id="prerequisites-">Prerequisites:</h3><ul><li><a href="https://nodejs.org/en/download/" rel="noopener">Download and install</a> NodeJS and NPM.</li><li>Have an IDE or text editor for making changes to snippets of code.</li><li>Have a Filebase account. If you don’t have one yet,</li></ul><p>For this tutorial we’ll be using Remix, a Javascript framework, to serve the webpage of our image gallery. Start by creating a Remix app by using the following command:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*UFs51LLZcRdMflnc" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>This command will ask you a series of questions. Here’s how we answered them:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*nKr8FafoSXHh_4aR" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><ul><li><strong>Where would you like to create your app?</strong> We chose ./image-gallery-dapp, but you can name your app anything and have it stored in any directory you’d like.</li><li><strong>What type of app do you want to create?</strong> Just the basics</li><li><strong>Where do you want to deploy?</strong> Remix App Server</li><li><strong>TypeScript or JavaScript?</strong> TypeScript</li><li><strong>Do you want me to run ‘npm install’?</strong> y</li></ul><p>Navigate into your new app directory:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*zTK6DbWdvGYvsASV" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Next, we’ll install Tailwind to be used with styling our app’s CSS:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*pZkQg9EvlTrWF9B2" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Then initialize your Tailwind package:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*IRBZYcJUQ0uPK4cy" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>This will create a new file called <code>tailwind.config.js</code>. Open this file in a text editor and enter the following content:</p><pre><code>module.exports = {
 mode: "jit",
 purge: ["./app/**/*.{ts,tsx}"],
 content: [],
 theme: {
 extend: {},
 },
 plugins: [],
};</code></pre><p>Next, open the <code>package.json</code> file and in the <code>scripts</code> section, replace the content with the following:</p><pre><code>"scripts": {
    "build": "npm run build:css &amp;&amp; remix build",
    "build:css": "tailwindcss -o ./app/tailwind.css",
    "dev": "concurrently \\"npm run dev:css\\" \\"remix dev\\"",
    "dev:css": "tailwindcss -o ./app/tailwind.css --watch",
    "postinstall": "remix setup node",
    "start": "remix-serve build"
  },</code></pre><p>Open the <code>app/root.tsx</code> file. Insert the following line at the top of the file:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*AHE-MqspMUob_VyL" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Then anywhere in the body of the <code>app/root.tsx</code> file, enter the following function lines:</p><pre><code>export const links: LinksFunction = () =&gt; {
  return [{ rel: "stylesheet", href: tailwindCSS }];
};</code></pre><p>Now let’s get our app up and running. Use the command:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*Yatx1PzYT7rS6vvD" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Your app will be running at <code>localhost:3000</code>. By default, it’ll look like this:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*wFriyMvjPobmJuVr" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Now let’s make it into our image gallery.</p><p>First, we need some images. To do this, navigate to <a href="https://console.filebase.com" rel="noopener">console.filebase.com</a>. If you don’t have an account already, <a href="http://filebase.com/signup" rel="noopener">sign up</a>, then log in. Select ‘Buckets’ from the left side bar menu, or navigate to <a href="http://console.filebase.com/buckets" rel="noopener">console.filebase.com/buckets</a>. Then select ‘Create Bucket’ in the top right corner to create a new bucket.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*MzQsSybrxvsMLaAt" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Enter a bucket name and choose the IPFS storage network to create the bucket.</p><p>In this guide, we’re calling the bucket <code>filebase-IPFS</code>.</p><blockquote>Typically, IPFS pinned files are stored on centralized cloud providers, like AWS. <br><br><strong><em>Using Filebase, all files that are pinned onto IPFS are actually being stored on the <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/introducing-support-for-ipfs-backed-by-decentralized-storage/">Sia</a> network.</em></strong> <br><br>This creates an environment where the data storage layer for Filebase's IPFS nodes are highly available, and most importantly, <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/deep-dives/deep-dive-geo-redundancy">geo-redundant.</a></blockquote><p><em>Bucket names must be unique across all Filebase users, be between 3 and 63 characters long, and can contain only lowercase characters, numbers, and dashes.</em></p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*MqyvnjfV39hia-8A" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Next, select the bucket from your list of buckets, then select ‘Upload’ in the top right corner to upload an image file.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*5UGKO92M3RKG6F_S" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Select an image to be uploaded. Once uploaded, it will be listed in the bucket.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*POvgxCzarU-1u2lZ" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>You can view the object’s IPFS CID in the CID column, or you can click on your uploaded object to display the metadata for the object, which includes the IPFS CID.</p><p>Choose the method you prefer, and take note of the IPFS CID.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*9n_Qd3pUEWlfMipe" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*-HF-d_9AhYO1U98y" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>Upload as many images as you’d like to use for your Image Gallery and take note of the CID for each one.</p><p>Now, let’s open the file in the app/routes directory called <code>index.tsx</code>. In this file, insert the following code:</p><pre><code>export default function gallery() {
  return (
&lt;body&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a target="_blank" href="Filebase_Networks_Icon"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs/IPFS_CID" alt="Filebase Networks Icon" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
  &lt;div class="desc"&gt;Filebase supports the IPFS, Sia, Skynet, and Storj Networks&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a target="_blank" href="Filebase_Icon"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs/IPFS_CID" alt="Filebase Icon" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
  &lt;div class="desc"&gt;The Filebase Logo&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
  &lt;a target="_blank" href="Filebase_Robot"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;img src="https://ipfs.filebase.io/ipfs/IPFS_CID" alt="Filebase Robot" width="400" height="400"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;
  &lt;div class="desc"&gt;The Filebase Robot&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
);
}</code></pre><p>Replace the <code>IPFS_CID</code> values with your IPFS CID’s from the images you uploaded to Filebase.</p><p>You can edit the size of each image by changing the <code>width</code> and <code>height</code> values.</p><p>You can also change the names and descriptions of each image by changing the <code>desc</code> values and the <code>alt</code> / <code>href</code> values.</p><p>Here’s what ours looks like:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/0*ntxft_Szn4MgT7NP" class="kg-image" alt="Build an Image Gallery App with IPFS and Tailwind CSS"></figure><p>From here, you can style your gallery however you’d like, using the Tailwind CSS package. For more information about Tailwind CSS and the customization options, see their documentation <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/docs/theme" rel="noopener">here.</a></p><h3 id="enjoy-5tb-of-free-ipfs-storage-for-one-month-using-code-ipfs-deploy-in-seconds-use-ipfs-today-">Enjoy 5TB of free IPFS storage for one-month (using code "IPFS")  <br><br><a href="https://emojipedia.org/floppy-disk/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">💾</a>  👉 <a href="https://filebase.com/signup">Deploy in-seconds, use IPFS today!</a></h3><p></p><p>Questions? Check out our excellent documentation <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/">found here</a>, or simply reach out to us: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a> or by <a href="https://discord.gg/xuX96JmChR">joining by our Discord</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Celebrate World Backup Day 2022 with 5TB free from Filebase!]]></title><description><![CDATA[March 31st is World Backup Day. As part of this annual celebration we're pleased to provide 5TB of decentralized cloud storage on Filebase FREE (for one-month).]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/celebrate-world-backup-day-2022-with-5tb-free-from-filebase/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6244b0043af9d2009d1f71fa</guid><category><![CDATA[Backups]]></category><category><![CDATA[World Backup Day]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 05:19:36 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/WBD.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/WBD.png" alt="Celebrate World Backup Day 2022 with 5TB free from Filebase!"><p></p><p>Did you know that 21% of people have never backed up their digital data? In the US alone, that means about 69,804,766 people could lose all of their photos, videos, and personal files if their hard drive crashes or is stolen.</p><p>March 31st is World Backup Day. As part of this annual celebration we're pleased to provide 5TB of decentralized cloud storage on Filebase FREE (for one-month).</p><p>You can take advantage of this offer by signing up for a new account with us using the promotion code <strong>WORLDBACKUP</strong></p><h2 id="why-bother-to-backup-your-data">Why Bother to Backup your Data?</h2><p>About 29% of all data loss is caused by an accident, such as an accidental deletion or an accident that compromises data stored on physical hardware. The remaining 69% of data loss is caused by disaster, malware or hardware failure. <br><br>It’s estimated that one-third of all computers have malicious software on them, and by the minute, 113 phones or devices are stolen or lost. If this data isn’t backed up, it’s gone and unretrievable. Irreplaceable data such as personal photos, videos, or important documents, are fundamental to our lives in today's digital age.</p><p>Ransomware can cause major headaches for those who are unlucky enough to fall victim to it. In a recent study, only 29% of victims were able to restore all their data following an attack. Of these 29%, 50% lost some files, 32% lost a significant portion of files, and 13% lost the entirety of their data.</p><h2 id="backup-vs-storage">Backup VS Storage</h2><p>When trying to safeguard your data, you should understand the difference between backup and storage. While backup protects your data when it's lost or stolen, storage leaves it vulnerable. Secure both locations to safeguard data from breaches.</p><p>Think of <strong>backup</strong> as making copies of content that you may need in the future. </p><p>Think of <strong>storage</strong> as a place where we keep content that we may not be using right now, but might use later.</p><p>Most modern SMB's and Enterprises follow a 3-2-1 backup strategy. </p><h2 id="the-3-2-1-backup-strategy">The 3-2-1 Backup Strategy</h2><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/3-2-1.png" class="kg-image" alt="Celebrate World Backup Day 2022 with 5TB free from Filebase!" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/3-2-1.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/3-2-1.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/3-2-1.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/3-2-1.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><ul><li><strong>Three Copies of Data</strong>: It is essential to keep a copy of the original data and at least two backups.</li><li><strong>Two Different Storage Types:</strong> Both copies of the backed up data should be kept on two separate storage types, such as an internal hard drive and an external hard drive, or a Network Attached Storage device and a cloud storage solution.</li><li><strong>One Copy Offsite: </strong>If you store at least one data copy offsite, you will be able to recover lost data in the event of a natural or geographical disaster.</li></ul><h2 id="achieve-3-2-1-with-filebase">Achieve 3-2-1 with Filebase</h2><p>At Filebase we believe that the future of cloud storage and disaster recovery is decentralized and geo-redundant. As the world’s first object storage platform powered by multiple decentralized storage networks, we form strategic partnerships with cutting-edge decentralized cloud storage networks. </p><p>We keep your files safe on thousands of servers worldwide enabling direct access from anywhere. These servers are the equivalent of miniature datacenters. </p><p>Data is stored redundantly across the globe instead of in a centralized location. Every file is encrypted and uploaded onto the decentralized web.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/centralized_decentralized.png" class="kg-image" alt="Celebrate World Backup Day 2022 with 5TB free from Filebase!" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/centralized_decentralized.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/centralized_decentralized.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/centralized_decentralized.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/centralized_decentralized.png 1920w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>In addition to our geo-redundant architecture, <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/what-is-filebase/s3-compatible-api">Filebase's S3-compatible API</a> integrates seamlessly with your existing business applications, tools, and SDKs. Filebase makes migrating data from centralized storage locations to Web3 simple with a few clicks.</p><h2 id="happy-world-backup-day-from-filebase-">Happy World Backup Day from Filebase!</h2><p>Take the World Backup Day Pledge and vow to backup your data today. Ensure your digital assets are protected from disaster and data loss by migrating them to the decentralized web.</p><p><strong>THE WORLD BACKUP DAY PLEDGE</strong></p><blockquote>I solemnly swear to backup my important documents and precious memories on March 31st.</blockquote><p>We want to ensure the safety of your important data. To make it convenient for you, we're giving all new paid members of Filebase 5 TB of decentralized storage (for one-month) free of charge!</p><p>To take advantage of this offer, simply <a href="https://filebase.com/">sign up</a> for a paid account and use the promotional code <strong>WORLDBACKUP </strong>upon upgrade.<br><br>Questions? Check out our excellent documentation <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/">found here</a>, or simply reach out to us: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a> or by <a href="https://discord.gg/xuX96JmChR">joining by our Discord</a>.<br><br></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase]]></title><description><![CDATA[With Thirdweb and Filebase you will learn how to instantly deploy NFT collection drops onto IPFS and decentralized storage at 1/10th the cost of your existing provider.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/release-an-nft-drop-and-deliver-geo-redundant-objects-on-ipfs-via-filebase/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">621d2c2bece80f009dd87753</guid><category><![CDATA[thirdweb]]></category><category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 21:29:24 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/NFTDrop_thirdweb.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/NFTDrop_thirdweb.png" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase"><p><a href="https://thirdweb.com/">Thirdweb</a> is an easy to use web dashboard for building Web3 applications seamlessly.</p><p>With Thirdweb, you will eliminate the burden of coding and deploying smart contracts, saving you time and effort. Because it's compatible with Filebase, you can instantly deploy NFT collection drops onto IPFS and decentralized storage utilizing an S3-Compatible API. Filebase ensures that all of your pinned objects remain highly-available, performant and deployed at 1/10th the cost of your existing provider.</p><p>Read below to learn how to create your own NFT Drop using Thirdweb and Filebase without any coding required, or complexity.</p><p>To get started, you will need:</p><ul><li>A crypto wallet, such as <a href="https://metamask.io/">MetaMask</a>.</li><li>Create a folder of images you’d like to use as NFT images for your drop.</li><li>Have a website you plan to use to embed the finished app on. This can be a simple Wordpress site, or a self-hosted website. This allows the public to have access to your NFT collection drop.</li><li>Have a Filebase account. If you don’t have one yet, <a href="http://filebase.com/signup">sign up here.</a> </li></ul><p>Start by logging into the <a href="https://thirdweb.com/dashboard">Thirdweb dashboard</a> and connect your crypto wallet of choice to Thirdweb.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-8.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-8.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-8.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-8.png 1173w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Once you’ve connected your wallet, select ‘Create Project’ to get started making your NFT Drop project.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-9.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-9.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-9.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-9.png 1172w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>In this tutorial, we’ll use the Mumbai Polygon Testnet network, but you can use any network you’d like. Once you select the Mumbai Polygon Testnet network, you may get a message saying your wallet has insufficient funds.</p><p>Use the ‘<a href="https://faucet.polygon.technology/">Get MATIC from faucet</a>’ option in the message to open the Polygon faucet to get some test currency. This is not real crypto currency, just a test currency for the test network. In the faucet window, select the Mumbai network, MATIC token, and enter your wallet address.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-10.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase"></figure><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-11.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase"></figure><p>Once the MATIC is shown in your wallet, move back to the Thirdweb dashboard screen. Give your project a name and a description. Select ‘Create’.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-12.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-12.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-12.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-12.png 1164w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>You will be prompted to authorize the transaction through your wallet.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-13.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase"></figure><p>Once authorized, your project is ready to be created. Select ‘Add Module’ from your project’s dashboard.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-14.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-14.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-14.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-14.png 1173w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>From the list of modules, select ‘Release Drop’.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-15.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-15.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-15.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-15.png 1166w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Select the type of NFT drop you’d like to create. For this guide, we’ll use a single NFT drop that uses unique, one of a kind NFTs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-16.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-16.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-16.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-16.png 1187w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Customize your NFT Drop module settings, including a name and description for your NFT drop, an image, symbol, and the primary sale recipient wallet address (where sales profits will be sent to).</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-17.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-17.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-17.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-17.png 1165w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Once finished, click ‘Deploy NFT Drop Module’. You will be prompted to authorize another transaction through your crypto wallet.</p><p>Next, confirm the permissions setting for your project:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-18.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-18.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-18.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-18.png 1170w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Our project is ready for NFTs to be uploaded!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-19.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-19.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-19.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-19.png 1208w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Before we can upload our NFTs, we need to upload the NFT image files to IPFS through Filebase.</p><p>We’ll start by uploading 3 images to Filebase for us to use. To do this, navigate to <a href="https://console.filebase.com/">console.filebase.com</a>. If you don’t have an account already, <a href="http://filebase.com/signup">sign up</a>, then log in.</p><p>Select ‘Buckets’ from the left side bar menu, or navigate to <a href="http://console.filebase.com/buckets">console.filebase.com/buckets</a>.</p><p>Select ‘Create Bucket’ in the top right corner to create a new bucket for your NFTs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-20.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-20.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-20.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-20.png 1600w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Enter a bucket name and choose the IPFS storage network to create the bucket. In this guide, we’re calling the bucket nft-collection.</p><p><em><strong>Note: Bucket names must be unique across all Filebase users, be between 3 and 63 characters long, and can contain only lowercase characters, numbers, and dashes.</strong></em></p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-21.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase"></figure><p>Next, select the bucket from your list of buckets, then select ‘Upload’ in the top right corner to upload your image files.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-5.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-5.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-5.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image-5.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-5.png 1899w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Select your images to be uploaded. Once uploaded, they will be listed in the bucket.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image.png 1908w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Click on each uploaded object to display the metadata for the object. Take note of the IPFS CID for each object.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-1.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-1.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-1.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image-1.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-1.png 1904w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Now we need to create a CSV file with each NFT’s metadata, which includes the IPFS CID we just took note of. Make a CSV with the following format:</p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>name</th>
<th>description</th>
<th>image</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1.png</td>
<td>Image 1 in the Filebase NFT Drop</td>
<td>ipfs://bafkreiha6dsjkd3jsdwdlla35aud3gzcykrvlhv4uxqnmxawsxefq75tjm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2.png</td>
<td>Image 2 in the Filebase NFT Drop</td>
<td>ipfs://bafkreieehizit7mnwgp4ptperkugwmam62ey2znohe56an3issdprj3dce</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3.png</td>
<td>Image 3 in the Filebase NFT Drop</td>
<td>ipfs://bafkreihm2qpjqbmhkyipqdgfi74lzgnkl55hxktfclidcbniveto2s37si</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table><!--kg-card-end: html--><p><strong><em>Note: Each NFT must be named in sequential order (0,1,2,3,4, etc) followed by the desired file extension (.png, .jpg, etc).</em></strong></p><p>Once you have your spreadsheet, select ‘Batch Upload’ from your Thirdweb project dashboard.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-25.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-25.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-25.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-25.png 1186w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Then, upload your CSV File.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-26.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-26.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-26.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-26.png 1219w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>You should see your NFT images populated with their metadata. Select ‘Next’ to continue.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-6.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-6.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-6.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-6.png 1224w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Decide which type of reveal you would like your NFT drop to have, either delayed or reveal upon mint, then upload your NFTs. You will be asked to authorize the transaction through your crypto wallet.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-28.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-28.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-28.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-28.png 1237w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Congrats! You’ve created an NFT collection! Now its time to set a claim condition so that users can own your NFTs.</p><p>Select the ‘Set Claim Condition’ button in the banner message.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-7.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-7.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-7.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-7.png 1170w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>For your claim condition, decide what cryptocurrency you want to sell your NFTs for, how much per NFT, and the supply you want to be claimable. You can also set a wait time between transactions, and a limit of how many NFTs can be claimed per transaction.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-30.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-30.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-30.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-30.png 1180w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Save your claim condition, and authorize the transaction through your crypto wallet.</p><p>You’re ready to release your drop! Thirdweb makes it easy to set your NFT drop as an embedded asset on any website.</p><p>Simply choose the ‘Embed’ tab from your project dashboard, then configure the IPFS Gateway to your preferred choice, and copy the Embed code to any website configuration.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-31.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-31.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-31.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-31.png 1190w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p> You can also see a preview of your Embedded drop on the bottom of the page.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-32.png" class="kg-image" alt="Release an NFT Drop and deliver geo-redundant objects on IPFS via Filebase" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-32.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-32.png 632w"></figure><p>Once embedded in a website, users can connect their Crypto wallet to the embedded Thirdweb app, and mint one of your NFTs!</p><p>Your NFT's are now <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/knowledge-base/deep-dives/deep-dive-geo-redundancy">geo-redundant</a>, highly-available via IPFS and stored onto the decentralized web using Filebase.</p><p>Questions? Check out our excellent documentation <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/">found here</a>, or simply reach out to us: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a> or by <a href="https://discord.gg/xuX96JmChR">joining by our Discord</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn to use Thirdweb to create an NFT ‘bundle collection' (Lootbox) while storing data easily on decentralized storage though Filebase, accessible via IPFS.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/creating-an-nft-lootbox-on-ipfs-with-filebase-and-thirdweb/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">621d3b54ece80f009dd877eb</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[thirdweb]]></category><category><![CDATA[NFT]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 15:38:12 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/04/February-Blog-Post-Images.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<blockquote>Lootboxes are virtual gift boxes that provide a random selection of items, typically used in video games with virtual in-game items. </blockquote><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/04/February-Blog-Post-Images.png" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"><p>In this tutorial, we’ll use <a href="https://thirdweb.com/">Thirdweb</a> to create the same kind of effect, but with an NFT collection. There will be a variety of NFTs with multiple copies, some with many copies and some with only a few copies to create a sense of ‘rarity’ amongst the different NFTs in the lootbox. </p><p>For example, if our lootbox collection has a total of 100 NFTs, and 75 of them are copies of NFT A, and 25 of them are NFT B, then the probability of getting NFT A is 75%, and the probability of getting NFT B is 25%, making NFT B more ‘rare’ than NFT A.</p><p>To execute this, we’ll use Thirdweb, an easy to use web dashboard for building Web3 applications, to create an NFT ‘bundle collection’, that we’ll use to create a ‘pack’. Each pack will have a randomly generated number which will determine if the NFT inside is either NFT A or NFT B. Our NFT metadata and assets will be stored in a <a href="https://filebase.com/blog/introducing-support-for-ipfs-backed-by-decentralized-storage/">Filebase IPFS bucket</a>.</p><h3 id="before-we-get-started-you-will-need-">Before we get started, you will need:</h3><ul><li>A cryptowallet, such as <a href="https://metamask.io/">MetaMask</a>.</li><li>Create a folder of images you’d like to use as NFT images for your lootbox.</li><li><a href="https://nodejs.org/en/download/">Download and install</a> NodeJS.</li><li>Have an IDE or text editor for making changes to snippets of code.</li><li>Have a Filebase account. If you don’t have one yet, <a href="http://filebase.com/signup">sign up here.</a></li></ul><p>For this project, we’ll be using the Polygon Mumbai Test network, which uses the cryptocurrency MATIC.</p><p>We’ll need some test MATIC for the transactions we’ll do later in this tutorial, so first let’s get some test currency by heading over to the <a href="https://faucet.polygon.technology/">Polygon Faucet</a>, selecting Mumbai and MATIC, and sending some to our wallet address.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-33.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"></figure><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-34.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"></figure><p>Next, let’s download the open source Github repo for this project:</p><p><code>git clone https://github.com/pointer-gg/thirdweb-lootbox-tutorial</code></p><p>Then, navigate inside of the newly downloaded project directory and install the project’s dependencies:</p><p><code>npm install</code></p><p>Start the project by starting the next.js dev server:</p><p><code>npm run dev</code></p><p>Login to the <a href="https://thirdweb.com/dashboard">Thirdweb dashboard</a> and connect your crypto wallet of choice to Thirdweb.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-35.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-35.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-35.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-35.png 1173w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Once you’ve connected your wallet, select ‘Create Project’ to get started making your NFT Lootbox project.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-36.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-36.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-36.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-36.png 1172w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Then, choose the ‘Mumbai’ Network for your project:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-37.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"></figure><p>Give your project a name and a description then click ‘Create’. You will be prompted to authorize a transaction through your crypto wallet which will use the MATIC we got from the faucet at the beginning of this tutorial:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-38.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-38.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-38.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-38.png 1167w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Navigate into the project directory we cloned from git earlier.</p><p>Create a .env file that will hold our cryptowallet’s private key to be referenced in our project’s scripts. Use the following format, replacing X with your crypto wallet’s private key. For instructions on how to get your wallet’s private key, see <a href="https://metamask.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360015289632-How-to-Export-an-Account-Private-Key">here</a>.</p><p><code>WALLET_PRIVATE_KEY=X</code></p><p>Next, install additional dependencies for our project’s scripts:</p><p><code>npm install @3rdweb/sdk ethers dotenv</code></p><p>Create a new script in the scripts directory called helpers.js. Input the following content into the script file:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { ThirdwebSDK } from "@3rdweb/sdk";
import ethers from "ethers";

// Read environment variables from .env
import dotenv from "dotenv";
dotenv.config();

const walletPrivateKey = process.env.WALLET_PRIVATE_KEY;

if (!walletPrivateKey) {
  console.error("Wallet private key missing")
  process.exit(1)
}

export const sdk = new ThirdwebSDK(
  new ethers.Wallet(
    // Wallet private key. NEVER CHECK THE KEY IN. ALWAYS USE ENVIRONMENT VARIABLES.
    process.env.WALLET_PRIVATE_KEY,
    // We use Polygon Mumbai network
    ethers.getDefaultProvider("&lt;https://winter-icy-sun.matic-testnet.quiknode.pro/f36aa318f8f806e4e15a58ab4a1b6cb9f9e9d9b9/&gt;")
  ),
);

const appAddress = '0x....'; // your project address from thirdweb

export async function getApp() {
  const app = await sdk.getAppModule(appAddress);
  return app;
}
</code></pre><p>Replace the <code>appAddress</code> with your project’s address from Thirdweb. You can find it on your project dashboard under your project’s name:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-39.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-39.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-39.png 928w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>This script initializes the project environment and sets up dependencies for use by our other scripts. It ‘helps’ the project, so that’s why it's called a helper script.</p><p>Next, create a script called 1-create-bundle-module.js in the scripts directory.</p><p>This script will create our bundle collection module that we’ll use to create our NFT collection. Input the following content into the script file:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { getApp } from './helpers.js';

async function main() {
  const app = await getApp();

  console.log('Deploying bundle collection module...');

  const bundleModule = await app.deployBundleModule({
    name: 'Lootbox Bundle',
    sellerFeeBasisPoints: 0,
  });

  console.log(`Deployed bundle collection module with address ${bundleModule.address}`);
}

try {
	await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error creating the bundle collection module", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Now let’s run this script to deploy the bundle collection module onto our project:</p><p><code>node scripts/1-create-bundle-module.js</code></p><p>You should get an output similar to the following. Note that your output might include some warnings about experimental features. These are coming from the Thirdweb SDK and are safe to disregard.</p><p><code>Deployed bundle collection module with address 0x0844EbdcFc584BdF42334D69CBEB6092f8Ba07Fb</code></p><p><em><strong>Take note of this bundle collection module address since we’ll need it for our next step.</strong></em></p><p>You can confirm that this was successful by looking at your project’s dashboard in Thirdweb:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-40.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-40.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-40.png 944w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Before we can upload our NFTs, we need to upload the NFT image files to IPFS through Filebase.</p><p>For this project, we’ll be uploading 3 images to Filebase for us to use. To do this, navigate to <a href="https://console.filebase.com/">console.filebase.com</a>. If you don’t have an account already, <a href="http://filebase.com/signup">sign up</a>, then log in.  Use code "IPFS" for a 5TB free trial for one-month. (5GB always free)</p><p>Select ‘Buckets’ from the left side bar menu, or navigate to <a href="http://console.filebase.com/buckets">console.filebase.com/buckets</a>.</p><p>Select ‘Create Bucket’ in the top right corner to create a new bucket for your NFTs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-41.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-41.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-41.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-41.png 1600w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Enter a bucket name and choose the IPFS storage network to create the bucket.</p><p>In this guide, we’re calling the bucket <code>nft-collection</code>.</p><p><em>Bucket names must be unique across all Filebase users, be between 3 and 63 characters long, and can contain only lowercase characters, numbers, and dashes.</em></p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-42.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"></figure><p>Next, select the bucket from your list of buckets, then select ‘Upload’ in the top right corner to upload your image files.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-4.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-4.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-4.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image-4.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-4.png 1899w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Select your images to be uploaded. Once uploaded, they will be listed in the bucket.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-3.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-3.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-3.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image-3.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-3.png 1908w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Click on each uploaded object to display the metadata for the object. Take note of the IPFS CID for each object.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-2.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/03/image-2.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/03/image-2.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1600/2022/03/image-2.png 1600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/image-2.png 1904w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Now it's time to mint our NFTs. To do so, we need a script that will create our NFT bundle. Create a new script in the <code>scripts</code> directory with the name <code>2-mint-bundle-nfts.js</code>. Enter the following content in the new script:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { sdk } from './helpers.js';

async function main() {
  // Paste in the address from when you created the bundle collection module
  const bundleModuleAddress = '0x...';
  const bundleModule = sdk.getBundleModule(bundleModuleAddress);

  console.log('Creating NFT batch...');

  const created = await bundleModule.createAndMintBatch([
    {
      metadata: {
        name: 'Filebase Blue Cloud',
        description: 'The first NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle',
        image: 'ipfs://bafkreiha6dsjkd3jsdwdlla35aud3gzcykrvlhv4uxqnmxawsxefq75tjm',
        properties: {
          rarity: 'a bit rare',
          fanciness: 7,
        }
      },
      supply: 50,
    },
    {
      metadata: {
        name: 'Filebase Orange Cloud',
        description: 'The second NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle',
        image: 'ipfs://bafkreieehizit7mnwgp4ptperkugwmam62ey2znohe56an3issdprj3dce',
        properties: {
          rarity: 'a bit rare',
          fanciness: 7,
        }
      },
      supply: 50,
    },
    {
      metadata: {
        name: 'Filebase Robot',
        description: 'The third NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle',
        image: 'ipfs://bafkreihm2qpjqbmhkyipqdgfi74lzgnkl55hxktfclidcbniveto2s37si',
        properties: {
          rarity: 'super rare!',
          fanciness: 10,
        }
      },
      supply: 10,
    }
  ]);

  console.log('NFTs created!')
  console.log(JSON.stringify(created, null, 2));
}

try {
  await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error minting the NFTs", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Replace the following values to match your configuration:</p><ul><li><strong>bundleModuleAddress:</strong> The bundle collection module address for your project’s bundle module. You can find it here:</li></ul><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-46.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-46.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-46.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-46.png 1194w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><ul><li><strong>name:</strong> The name for each NFT you’re creating.</li><li><strong>description</strong>: The description for each NFT you’re creating.</li><li><strong>image:</strong> The IPFS CID you copied from the Filebase console, in the format ipfs://[CID]</li></ul><p>Once you’ve configured the script to match your NFT Lootbox collection’s information, run the script:</p><p><code>node scripts/2-mint-bundle-nfts.js</code></p><p>You will receive an output similar to this:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">NFTs created!
[
{
"creator": "0x9C33cD8e20c595Aad0C04ae58414916e5529ff6a",
"supply": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x32"
},
"metadata": {
"name": "Filebase Blue Cloud",
"description": "The first NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle",
"image": "https://cloudflare-ipfs.com/ipfs/bafkreiha6dsjkd3jsdwdlla35aud3gzcykrvlhv4uxqnmxawsxefq
75tjm",
"properties": {
"rarity": "a bit rare",
"fanciness": 7
},
"id": "0",
"uri": "ipfs://QmWfduLinYFSX7wXtH6GAN28jsH7qkZgXnx4Q4sK1Kcwjo/0"
},
"ownedByAddress": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x00"
},
"underlyingType": 0
},
{
"creator": "0x9C33cD8e20c595Aad0C04ae58414916e5529ff6a",
"supply": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x32"
},
"metadata": {
"name": "Filebase Orange",
"description": "The second NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle",
"image": "https://cloudflare-ipfs.com/ipfs/bafkreieehizit7mnwgp4ptperkugwmam62ey2znohe56an3issdpr
j3dce",
"properties": {
"rarity": "a bit rare",
"fanciness": 7
},
"id": "1",
"uri": "ipfs://QmWfduLinYFSX7wXtH6GAN28jsH7qkZgXnx4Q4sK1Kcwjo/1"
},
"ownedByAddress": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x00"
},
"underlyingType": 0
},
{
"creator": "0x9C33cD8e20c595Aad0C04ae58414916e5529ff6a",
"supply": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x0a"
},
"metadata": {
"name": "Filebase Robot",
"description": "The third NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle",
"image": "https://cloudflare-ipfs.com/ipfs/bafkreihm2qpjqbmhkyipqdgfi74lzgnkl55hxktfclidcbniveto2
s37si",
"properties": {
"rarity": "super rare!",
"fanciness": 10
},
"id": "2",
"uri": "ipfs://QmWfduLinYFSX7wXtH6GAN28jsH7qkZgXnx4Q4sK1Kcwjo/2"
},
"ownedByAddress": {
"type": "BigNumber",
"hex": "0x00"
},
"underlyingType": 0
}
]
</code></pre><p>You will also see the NFTs listed in your Bundle Module on your Thirdweb dashboard:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-47.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-47.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-47.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-47.png 1187w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Your collection is now live, and you can view it on <a href="https://testnets.opensea.io/">testnets.opensea.io</a> by searching for your Bundle Collection Module Address:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-48.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-48.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-48.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-48.png 1600w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>You can click on any of these NFTs and view their collection rarity and other metadata:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-49.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb"></figure><p>Now we need to create the Lootbox pack module to bundle our NFTs into a pack. Create a new script in your project’s <code>scripts</code> directory called <code>3-pack-module.js</code> and enter the following content:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { getApp } from './helpers.js';

async function main() {
  const app = await getApp();

  console.log('Deploying pack module...');

  const packModule = await app.deployPackModule({
    name: 'Lootbox Pack',
    sellerFeeBasisPoints: 0,
  });

  console.log(`Deployed pack module with address ${packModule.address}`);
}

try {
  await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error creating the pack module", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Now, run the 3-pack-module.js script:</p><p><code>node scripts/3-pack-module.js</code></p><p>You will receive the following output:</p><p><code>Deployed pack module with address 0x6164eE4fC3173773B5e8a8A4745c67C3DAc0025b</code></p><p>Now that we have the pack module created on our project, we need to add our NFTs into the pack.</p><p>To do this, we’ll need to create another script in the <code>scripts</code> directory called <code>4-create-pack-from-bundle.js</code> with the following content:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { sdk } from './helpers.js';

async function main() {
  const bundleModuleAddress = '0x...'; // your bundle module address
  const bundleModule = sdk.getBundleModule(bundleModuleAddress);

  const packModuleAddress = '0x...'; // your pack module address
  const packModule = sdk.getPackModule(packModuleAddress);

  console.log('Getting all NFTs from bundle...');
  const nftsInBundle = await bundleModule.getAll();

  console.log('NFTs in bundle:');
  console.log(nftsInBundle);

  console.log('Creating a pack containing the NFTs from bundle...');
  const created = await packModule.create({
    assetContract: bundleModuleAddress,
    metadata: {
      name: 'Filebase NFT Lootbox',
      image: 'ipfs://bafkreihm2qpjqbmhkyipqdgfi74lzgnkl55hxktfclidcbniveto2s37si',
    },
    assets: nftsInBundle.map(nft =&gt; ({
      tokenId: nft.metadata.id,
      amount: nft.supply,
    })),
  });

  console.log('Pack created!')
  console.log(created);
}

try {
  await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error minting the NFTs", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Replace the following values to match your configuration:</p><ul><li><strong>bundleModuleAddress:</strong> Your Bundle Module Address</li><li><strong>packModuleAddress:</strong> Your Pack Module Address</li><li><strong>name:</strong> A name for your NFT Lootbox.</li><li><strong>image:</strong> An IPFS link using an IPFS CID for the image of your IPFS lootbox. In this example, we’re using one of the IPFS CIDs for one of the NFTs in the lootbox. If you’d like to use a different image, upload a new image to your Filebase IPFS bucket and use the CID associated with that image.</li></ul><p>Next, run this script to create our Lootbox pack:</p><p><code>node scripts/4-create-pack-from-bundle.js</code></p><p>You should receive the following output:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">Pack created!
{
id: '0',
metadata: {
id: '0',
uri: 'ipfs://QmZCfK816WRp93WsxAjpbpF64kaB5qeMXwzMpYK3DJanWc/0'
},
creator: '0x9C33cD8e20c595Aad0C04ae58414916e5529ff6a',
currentSupply: BigNumber { _hex: '0x6e', _isBigNumber: true },
openStart: 2022-02-21T17:41:45.000Z
}
</code></pre><p>You can find your pack on <a href="https://testnets.opensea.io/">testnets.opensea.io</a> by searching for the pack module address:</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-50.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-50.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w1000/2022/02/image-50.png 1000w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-50.png 1269w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Note that the collection shows ‘110 owned’. This is the total number of NFTs we created when minting our NFTs for this bundle, since we made 50 copies of NFTs 1 and 2, and 10 copies of NFT 3.</p><p>Now, to open a pack we need a way to generate a random number for one of our pack’s NFTs.</p><p>To do this, we’ll use Chainlink, a popular tool for random selection of smart contracts. To use Chainlink, you need tokens called LINKs. Since we’re using the Mumbai test network, we’ll use <a href="http://faucets.chain.link/">faucets.chain.link</a> to get some test LINKs to use.</p><p>Select the Polygon Mumbai network, enter your wallet address, and request your test LINKs.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-51.png" class="kg-image" alt="Creating an NFT Lootbox on IPFS with Filebase and Thirdweb" srcset="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/size/w600/2022/02/image-51.png 600w, https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/02/image-51.png 992w" sizes="(min-width: 720px) 720px"></figure><p>Now that we have our test LINKs, we need to deposit them into our Lootbox project. Create a new script in the <code>scripts</code> directory called <code>5-deposit-links.js</code> with the following content:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { ethers } from "ethers";
import { sdk } from "./helpers.js";

async function main() {
  const packModuleAddress = '0x...'; // your pack module address
  const packModule = sdk.getPackModule(packModuleAddress);

  console.log('Depositing link...')

  // LINK uses 18 decimals, same as Eth. So this gives us the amount to use for 2 LINK
  const amount = ethers.utils.parseEther('2');

  await packModule.depositLink(amount);
  console.log('Deposited!')

  const balance = await packModule.getLinkBalance();
  console.log(balance);
}

try {
  await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error depositing the LINK", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Replace the <strong>packModuleAddress</strong> value with your pack module address.</p><p>Now it’s time to open one of our Lootbox packs. Create another new script in your scripts directory called 6-open-packs.js with the following content:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">import { sdk } from "./helpers.js";

async function main() {
  const packModuleAddress = '0x...';
  const packModule = sdk.getPackModule(packModuleAddress);

  console.log('Opening the pack...');
  const opened = await packModule.open('0');
  console.log('Opened the pack!');
  console.log(opened);
}

try {
  await main();
} catch (error) {
  console.error("Error opening the pack", error);
  process.exit(1);
}
</code></pre><p>Replace the <strong>packModuleAddress</strong> value with your pack module address. Run your open-pack.js script to open your pack:</p><p><code>node scripts/6-open-pack.js</code></p><p>You should receive the following output:</p><pre><code class="language-jsx">Opening the pack...
Opened the pack!
[
{
name: 'Filebase Robot',
description: 'The third NFT in the Filebase Lootbox Bundle',
image: 'https://cloudflare-ipfs.com/ipfs/bafkreihm2qpjqbmhkyipqdgfi74lzgnkl55hxktfclidcbniveto2s37si',
properties: { rarity: super rare!, fanciness: 10 },
id: '2',
uri: 'ipfs://QmWfduLinYFSX7wXtH6GAN28jsH7qkZgXnx4Q4sK1Kcwjo/2'
}
]
</code></pre><p>You opened your first Lootbox successfully! You can call this script a few more times to collect all the different NFTs in your Lootbox collection. If you check <a href="https://testnets.opensea.io/">testnets.opensea.io</a>, you can see the number of packs you own has decreased, but the number of NFTs owned has increased.</p><p>Questions? Check out our excellent documentation <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/">found here</a>, or simply reach out to us: <a href="mailto:hello@filebase.com">hello@filebase.com</a> or by <a href="https://discord.gg/xuX96JmChR">joining by our Discord</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Using Tableland SQL To Track Object Name, Type, and IPFS CID of Objects Stored in an Filebase Bucket]]></title><description><![CDATA[Learn how to use Tableland SQL to track object name, type, and IPFS CID of objects stored in an IPFS Filebase bucket.]]></description><link>https://filebase.com/blog/using-tableland-sql-to-track-object-name-type-and-ipfs-cid-of-objects-stored-in-an-ipfs-filebase-bucket/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">621d2b64ece80f009dd8772c</guid><category><![CDATA[ipfs]]></category><category><![CDATA[SQL]]></category><dc:creator><![CDATA[The Filebase Team]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 17:00:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/Tableland-2.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://filebase.com/blog/content/images/2022/03/Tableland-2.png" alt="Using Tableland SQL To Track Object Name, Type, and IPFS CID of Objects Stored in an Filebase Bucket"><p><a href="https://tableland.xyz/">Tableland</a> is an SQL database and network protocol built for use on the Ethereum network. Tableland can be used to store anything from tokenURI metadata to NFT extensions or DAO tools. Tables created and stored with Tableland utilize a user’s Ethereum wallet address for authentication, so no usernames, passwords, or access keys required.</p><p>Tableland can be used to record and track metadata for objects stored in a Filebase IPFS bucket. Objects stored on the IPFS network have an associated IPFS CID which is unique to each file, but isn’t easily identifiable like typical file IDs or storage paths are. To solve this, you can create a database with Tableland that tracks your objects and their associated file name, type, and IPFS CID so you can query it whenever you need to quickly reference an object.</p><p>Read below to learn how to use Tableland SQL to track object name, type, and IPFS CID of objects stored in an IPFS Filebase bucket.</p><h2 id="prerequisites-">Prerequisites:</h2><ul><li>Sign up for Tableland early access using their <a href="https://docs.tableland.xyz/building/quick-start">Quick Start</a> instructions. This process involves having your Ethereum public wallet address whitelisted for use with the Tableland API.</li><li>Download and install the Tableland CLI tool: <code>npm i -g @textile/tableland-cli</code></li><li>Have Your Filebase Access and Secret Keys. Learn how to view your access keys <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/getting-started-guides/getting-started-guide#working-with-access-keys">here</a>.</li><li>Have a Filebase bucket created on the IPFS network. For instructions on how to create a bucket on the IPFS network, see <a href="https://docs.filebase.com/what-is-filebase/our-ecosystem/storage-networks/ipfs#how-do-i-store-data-on-ipfs-through-filebase">here</a>.</li></ul><p>Once your ETH wallet address has been whitelisted for use with Tableland, you will need to grab your private key string to interact with Ethereum to create a new table.</p><p>You can follow <a href="https://metamask.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/360015289632-How-to-Export-an-Account-Private-Key">these instructions</a> to grab your private key string from Metamask.</p><p>Next, export your private key string as an environment variable so you don’t have to keep pasting it.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><code>export TBL_PRIVATE_KEY=[PRIVATE_KEY_STRING]</code></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Replace <code>PRIVATE_KEY_STRING</code> with your private key string.</p><p>Then, use the following CLI command to create a table on Tableland called AssetTracker.</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><code>tableland create &quot;CREATE TABLE AssetTracker (id INT PRIMARY KEY, name TEXT, type TEXT, cid TEXT, provider TEXT, url TEXT);&quot; --description=&quot;Filebase Asset Tracker&quot;</code></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>The response from that query is your new table name! You’ll need to reference that later to update and query the table. It should look something like the following:</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><code>{ &quot;name&quot;: &quot;assettracker_192&quot; }</code></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>If you have your own API keys for Infura, Alchemy, etc you can avoid the warning message that was printed with the above command. See <code>tableland create —help</code> for details.</p><p>Then, insert some data to query using the query CLI command:</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><code>tableland query &quot;INSERT INTO assettracker_192 VALUES (0, 'filebase_robot.png', 'PNG', 'bafybeict7kegxaugjue5rcys65islddi2rnzmj2hh2wfq3wynf7t772hy4', 'filebase.com', 'https://bafybeict7kegxaugjue5rcys65islddi2rnzmj2hh2wfq3wynf7t772hy4.ipfs.dweb.link');&quot;</code></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>Replace <code>assettracker_192</code> with the value you received in the previous step. The following table has some additional objects you might want to include.</p><p><strong>Example Database Table:</strong></p><!--kg-card-begin: html--><table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>id</th>
<th>name</th>
<th>type</th>
<th>cid</th>
<th>provider</th>
<th>url</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>filebase_robot.png</td>
<td>PNG</td>
<td>bafybeict7kegxaugjue5rcys65islddi2rnzmj2hh2wfq3wynf7t772hy4</td>
<td><a href="https://filebase.com">https://filebase.com</a></td>
<td><a href="https://bafybeict7kegxaugjue5rcys65islddi2rnzmj2hh2wfq3wynf7t772hy4.ipfs.dweb.link">https://bafybeict7kegxaugjue5rcys65islddi2rnzmj2hh2wfq3wynf7t772hy4.ipfs.dweb.link</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>filebase_logo.png</td>
<td>PNG</td>
<td>bafkreighyv7jppuyen6kvdw3lhnleydibj44wej3ejq2j7ndwd3hsa7oam</td>
<td><a href="http://filebase.com">http://filebase.com</a></td>
<td><a href="https://bafkreighyv7jppuyen6kvdw3lhnleydibj44wej3ejq2j7ndwd3hsa7oam.ipfs.dweb.link">https://bafkreighyv7jppuyen6kvdw3lhnleydibj44wej3ejq2j7ndwd3hsa7oam.ipfs.dweb.link</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table><!--kg-card-end: html--><p>To query the database, use the following CLI command:</p><!--kg-card-begin: markdown--><p><code>tableland query &quot;SELECT * FROM assettracker_192;&quot;</code></p>
<!--kg-card-end: markdown--><p>This example queries all entries in the database. You can modify this to reflect your desired query for a single object or a certain criteria of objects.</p><p>For more information on Tableland, check out their documentation <a href="https://docs.tableland.xyz">here</a>.</p><h2 id="resources">Resources</h2><p>Experience the power of Web3 in seconds: <a href="https://console.filebase.com/signup?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=MountainDuck">Get started with 5GB of free object storage with no expirations and no trials.</a></p><p>Need more storage?  Use code <em><em><strong><strong>"WEB3WELCOME"</strong></strong></em></em> for 1TB of storage (your first month free) on us!</p><p>For more information on Tableland, check out their documentation <a href="https://docs.tableland.xyz/">here</a>, and <a href="https://blog.textile.io/tableland-is-coming-build-web3-with-sql/">blog</a>.</p><p><a href="https://docs.filebase.com/configurations/cli-tools-and-resources/tableland">Filebase - Tableland Docs Section</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>