<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:cc="http://cyber.law.harvard.edu/rss/creativeCommonsRssModule.html">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[The Sia Blog - Medium]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Decentralized storage — Sia, Skynet, and cryptocurrency. - Medium]]></description>
        <link>https://blog.sia.tech?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/proxy/1*TGH72Nnw24QL3iV9IOm4VA.png</url>
            <title>The Sia Blog - Medium</title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
        </image>
        <generator>Medium</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 17:14:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://blog.sia.tech/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <webMaster><![CDATA[yourfriends@medium.com]]></webMaster>
        <atom:link href="http://medium.superfeedr.com" rel="hub"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grants Program Update, July 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-july-2023-470ad256ba66?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/470ad256ba66</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[grants-for-nonprofit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 19:22:27 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-07-17T19:22:16.784Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*egaqTngHtLql72lUSjfbQg.png" /></figure><p>The Sia Foundation has grant funding available for community contributors! The Grants Program was created to fund research, development, developer tools, and anything else that will support and further our mission of user-owned data while enriching the Sia ecosystem.</p><p>Just design a proposal that meets our requirements, submit to our forums, and wait for review by our grants committee. If your grant gets approved, you’re on your way to creating the next great project on the Sia storage network.</p><p>Check out <a href="https://sia.tech/grants">our site</a> for more info.</p><h3>The Current State of Grants</h3><p>Since we posted three months ago for <a href="https://medium.com/sia-tech/grants-program-update-april-2023-the-six-month-check-in-d9c3404d7441">our last grants update</a>, a lot of great grants have graced the committee resulting on four approvals, three requests for more info, two rejections, and two proposals waiting for consideration. For the purposes of this article, we’ll stick to talking about the approvals. But you can jump on over the our forums at your leisure to check out the thread for any proposal, see the committee responses, and check up on progress reports as each month passes.</p><p>The committee is getting better at determining what it wants out of a grant, and we’re improving our logistics to ensure smooth meetings, efficient onboarding, and happy grantees. Let’s jump right into our approvals.</p><h3>New Proposal: Sia Satellite 2</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-sia-satellite-ii/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A followup to the first Sia Satellite grant, with new additions and improvements for the software.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>We’re honored to have our first returning grantee. The grant for Sia Satellite 2 will improve the software in big ways. Mike demonstrated his ability to deliver over the first few months that the Foundation entrusted him with grant funds, and we’re really excited to see more progress on this important community project.</p><h3>New Proposal: Sia Atomic Swap Feasibility Study</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-sia-atomic-swap-with-adaptor-signatures-feasibility-study/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>This grant wants to investigate the feasibility of Siacoin atomic swaps.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>This grant was approved with a number of community members expressing their support.</p><h3>New Proposal: SiaShare</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-siashare/340">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>This grant wants to create an end-to-end encrypted file sharing site.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>A super simple interface for sending encrypted files has seen support before, and we’re excited to see how this grant develops. The grantee mjmay08 has experience working in the Sia ecosystem, having developed a couple of Skynet-based apps for past hackathons.</p><h3>New Proposal: ARC Data Wallet</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-arc-data-wallet/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A browser extension to manage your Sia wallet and files.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>The Grants Committee posed a couple of concerns to the ARC team, namely regarding the location of the Sia node as well as requiring more details on the budget request. Upon hearing their justification and answers, their proposal was approved.</p><h3>Coming Next</h3><p>We encourage the community to provide their feedback and ask questions on the <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/">Sia Forum</a>! Community contribution and input is the best way to push proposals and projects to the next level.</p><p>You can see the list of all proposals <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/c/foundation/grants/">here</a>, and our proposal requirements <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/about-the-grants-category/">here</a>. See you next month!</p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steveisonline on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=470ad256ba66" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-july-2023-470ad256ba66">Grants Program Update, July 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Sia, July 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-july-2023-f89499c4a916?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/f89499c4a916</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cloud-storage]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2023 21:04:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-07-05T21:04:14.391Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*adEjulSiz9Xed-w5.png" /></figure><p>We’re back with the State of Sia, a monthly installment looking at development and team updates for The Sia Foundation.</p><p>Quickly, I’d like to note that while we have skipped a couple of months of Grants Program updates, we’ll be back in force for July. Expect to see that back at it’s regular mid-month time slot in a couple weeks.</p><p>Beyond that, summer marches on for us here at the Foundation. We mentioned last month that we’re looking into hiring a Developer Relations expert, and things are going exceedingly well there. We hope to have some specific info for you next month, but the Foundation team will be growing shortly.</p><p>Our renterd beta has been going smoothly, with excellent feedback on the UI/UX and all the new functionality baked in.</p><p>hostd has officially <a href="https://blog.sia.tech/introducing-hostd-871d7fea23de">entered beta</a> with its 0.1.0 release. It’s an extremely stable version, complete with a great new UI just like all our new apps, and delivers some massive performance upgrades over what hosts currently see.</p><p>Our <a href="https://sia.tech/transparency/2023-q2.pdf">Q2 report</a> is also available now — the transparency report is a critical review of Foundation happenings, giving a free look into major milestones and money spent over the past three months.</p><h3>Development</h3><p>All public repos can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation">here</a>.</p><h3>renterd</h3><p>renterd will be our new stand-alone renter. The renterd repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd">here</a>, and the app is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/releases/tag/v0.1.0-beta">available in beta</a>.</p><ul><li>upload improvements got merged, saw pretty nice 3x improvement (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/390">Link</a>)</li><li>upload improvements follow up to further improve upload performance (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/395">Link</a>) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/433">Link</a>)</li><li>download improvements will get merged soon, really great improvement there, at least 5x but harder to compare (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/405">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*IvisjxWmC-Ew2V0M.png" /></figure><ul><li>the autopilot.json config file was the last config that had to move over to the bus, everything is in the bus now (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/428">Link</a>)</li><li>extend the /api/autopilot/status endpoint with some info to be used by the UI soon (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/443">Link</a>)</li><li>various fixes to improve contract churn, churn is when a contract gets removed from the contract set, which (in many cases) triggers needless migrations (repairs) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/420">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused revision mismatch errors on uploads (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/385">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where hosts appeared as offline due to the machine idling or the bus crashing (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/387">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue that caused contracts to not renew due a “duplicate key constraint” failing (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/393">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue in SQLite which caused renewals to randomly fail due to a unique constraint violation (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/412">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where deleting objects wouldn’t work through the worker’s objects endpoint (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/419">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where a contract without funds couldn’t be refreshed/renewed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/427">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue in price scoring where hosts were punished more than necessary (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/434">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where some interactions with hosts were considered unsuccessful even though it wasn’t the host’s fault, resulting in a lower interaction score than necessary (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/435">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*sCyDiqIE-8qYksUF.png" /></figure><ul><li>Stopped accounting for redundancy in the download gouging code since downloads don’t have any overhead. Leading to hosts being able to have higher download prices before being considered gouging on download prices (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/439">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where renewing/refreshing contracts sometimes failed while uploading or migrating data (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/440">Link</a>)</li><li>Added support for filtering hosts by usability in autopilot’s /hostsendpoint (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/394">Link</a>)</li><li>Prepare the bus for upload packing (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/397">Link</a>) and (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/400">Link</a>)</li><li>Automatically resync the bus if the consensus change ID is invalid (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/399">Link</a>)</li><li>Free used unspent outputs in the wallet after 24 hours to prevent them from being locked up forever (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/406">Link</a>)</li><li>Associate objects/slabs with the contract set that uploaded them to improve accuracy of computing slab health for a given set (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/415">Link</a>)</li><li>Interrupt migrations if the contract set was updated mid-migration to avoid unnecessary migrations (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/417">Link</a>)</li><li>Started recording the size of a contract locally to allow returning it through the bus’ contracts endpoints (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/426">Link</a>)</li><li>Added support for deleting folders (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/429">Link</a>)</li><li>Reduce contract churn by not dropping contracts from the set after failing to renew for the first time and instead give them half the renew window before dropping them (Link))</li><li>Added a migrations table to the database to keep track of migrations that were already run (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/450">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>renterd ui</h3><p>The repos containing the various UIs being worked on can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web">here</a>. A full detailed changelog can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/releases">here</a>.</p><ul><li>The autopilot config no longer defaults, it now must be configured by the user (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/dc23d8c0d88ae29868b5870246f88277f8b5256e">Link</a>)</li><li>The autopilot status endpoint has been removed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/234a40a8df977910f7d583793969c0d5bf636b77">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*FHi7q2Lb9K8DzawD.png" /></figure><ul><li>The contracts table now includes a data size column (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/40d856d624bcd8e16d1968e6bb5d74ed5e7c614b">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where opening the file search feature would crash the UI (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/dfc1129ca189bd1b52999c0ada10ede0be120398">Link</a>)</li><li>Wallet send flow now properly discards transaction if an error occurs during signing or broadcasting (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/54b1b445d652efc06c2ea86fbc8622140a1ec59e">Link</a>)</li><li>Files stats now show a breakdown of file size with and without redundancy and also with repairs (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/04c8cd011b75c60f5be44ba47ef96115432fce47">Link</a>)</li><li>The hosts explorer now supports filtering by usable and unusable (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/8c2a95daf115ca8a914de2cdf2132f6b923e8ff7">Link</a>)</li><li>Numbers are now displayed and entered in localized format (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/06e7e1c52b5d1a01486fa4e5fc0566469ef522b5">Link</a>)</li><li>Currency options now include CAD, AUS, RUB, and CNY (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/000db6a654c047a124c07ed511c9843fad9183c1">Link</a>)</li><li>Dates and times are now displayed in a localized format (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/06e7e1c52b5d1a01486fa4e5fc0566469ef522b5">Link</a>)</li><li>The wallet now shows a balance evolution graph (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/33cd3b5404b1f33e7bac4aa03928b8b328040cf0">Link</a>)</li><li>The transaction details dialog title is now based on the specific type (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/33cd3b5404b1f33e7bac4aa03928b8b328040cf0">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>hostd</h3><p>hostd is the app you’ll be using to rent out your excess storage space to the Sia network. The hostd repo is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd">public</a>, with a beta out now.</p><ul><li>released hostd beta v0.1.0 (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/releases/tags/v0.1.0">Link</a>)</li><li>Add configurable sector read cache (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/81">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/83">Link</a>)</li><li>Refactored revise contract improving performance and atomicity (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/90">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed panics in RHP3 (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/885c3ac5fa24b93a71f2046a5b0b4ca8a6f3e312">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/e62eda3595bee9d9047868e115bdb374797b50ee">Link</a>)</li><li>Added alerts to notify the host of issues (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/66">Link</a>)</li><li>Changed HOSTD_WALLET_SEED environment variable to HOSTD_SEED to match renterd.</li><li>Changed collateral setting to a multiplier of storage price (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/79">Link</a>)</li><li>Added handling for consensus subscription errors to rescan the blockchain (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/8bbd8876cd18a761e5e2999e5a1ebe43906939cc">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/c76380364e7635bd3c337fe0015b3db50471b531">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/d5527e7e795be8f8c1df21cccd6e427119d53709">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/825d3d2564501b7c5b3b813532e202456936d7e5">Link</a>)</li><li>Fix volumes being marked as unavailable when deletion fails (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/41b17a0894e5df33eabe86f807a31edb07c09bbf">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*WJnP6i9lZelczZwV.png" /></figure><ul><li>Fixed bugs in metrics when force removing volumes. (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/f86314662fc17df1ff922460c02b3fcfadfeee2d">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/f577c52c7862f5ed459d145f9a7220d14b0f5e75">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed alignment on 32-bit systems. While we don’t support 32-bit operating systems, hostd will no longer crash.</li></ul><h3>hostd ui</h3><p>A full detailed changelog can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/releases">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Home page storage metric card now shows physical sectors instead of contract sectors (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/09072b7c50bfe34bdfc5c28f805fd0b000ebb6cd">Link</a>)</li><li>hostd now features alerts. Alerts notify the user to important contract and storage events. (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/867763b20cf332c04d291662bc5c2bf68a45dc8f">Link</a>)</li><li>Collateral configuration setting is now a multiple of storage price (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/f8723a70ae203887108b7f36367a8436e8609b47">Link</a>)</li><li>The contracts page now properly instructs the user to configure and announce the host when there are no contracts (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/b4e6d67c1900f44255cdc63bd3f5f26639998255">Link</a>)</li><li>The host announcement dialog now shows the correct fee amount (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/e76398fb4aa7d552e1caf33a20ee732354affa46">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where flat lines were not showing up on graphs (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/2e1e6662a69452e6a5e74650a32361c33f6e7f98">Link</a>)</li><li>Pricing metrics now show proper values (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/d9112931a9093caaf64550598c8051b276d5dca8">Link</a>)</li><li>Numbers are now displayed and entered in localized format (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/06e7e1c52b5d1a01486fa4e5fc0566469ef522b5">Link</a>)</li><li>Currency options now include CAD, AUS, RUB, and CNY (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/000db6a654c047a124c07ed511c9843fad9183c1">Link</a>)</li><li>Dates and times are now displayed in a localized format (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/06e7e1c52b5d1a01486fa4e5fc0566469ef522b5">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*-dhg1POa8buPYtQR.png" /></figure><ul><li>The volume creation dialog now allows selecting the location via text input (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/cad2fa5a2db2059d3d49cae7eaf4e4821e12cbaa">Link</a>)</li><li>Pricing metrics are now in the same units as their corresponding configuration values (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/46372064852547504b0ee393c127d8ff985a794e">Link</a>)</li><li>Contracts can now be sorted by expiration height (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/198df6a6b17e7a47b4afa83ae64e01e4034d9b1f">Link</a>)</li><li>The metrics page now remembers selected data time span, interval, and date range (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/32f69b4fe2f3bd60a6f172204bb5bf8ea5f99050">Link</a>)</li><li>The Node overview now features a logs panel that shows the last 100 actions (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/ae32be109529b6db3695a4233ad5a7f0f00ce827">Link</a>)</li><li>The transaction details dialog title is now based on the specific type (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/33cd3b5404b1f33e7bac4aa03928b8b328040cf0">Link</a>)</li><li>Metrics now show the correct interval with start and end date time details (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/198df6a6b17e7a47b4afa83ae64e01e4034d9b1f">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>walletd</h3><p>walletd is our brand new wallet-only software. Find the public repo <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/walletd">here</a>.</p><p>walletd has been released into alpha for public testing, with a myriad of commits made to master <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/walletd/commits/master">this month</a>.</p><h3>ledger</h3><ul><li>Implemented some fixes that Ledger requested for the Stax app (<a href="https://github.com/siafoundation/app-sia-x/pull/3">Link</a>)<br>– added status screens for all actions like “Transaction Signed” or “Address Verification Cancelled”, fixed a few miscellaneous bugs.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/0*ziVImn2suJfE8MGh.png" /></figure><h3>Future work</h3><p>Here’s a quick, unstructured peek at some work we’re planning on for July.</p><ul><li>working on adding batched writes to the core chain database (<a href="https://github.com/siafoundation/core/tree/add-batching">Link</a>)</li><li>upload packing</li><li>hostd: release hostd beta v0.2.0, improve data integrity tools: remove corrupt sectors, automate integrity checks, increase performance and stability</li><li>continuing to iterate on walletd</li></ul><h3>That’s all folks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/710/0*0MeOkuuGyXv-T4cw.jpeg" /></figure><p>The Foundation team is going to keep working hard through the summer, while enjoying a vacation here and there. The app-suite that we’re releasing and updating over the next few months is going to position the Foundation and the entire community well for years to come, and we’ll have a few more surprises here and there for you.</p><p>Take care, and see you next month.</p><p><a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>, <a href="mailto:hello@sia.tech">Email</a></p><h3>Steve</h3><p>@steveisonline on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=f89499c4a916" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-july-2023-f89499c4a916">The State of Sia, July 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Introducing hostd]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/introducing-hostd-871d7fea23de?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/871d7fea23de</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralized-storage]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Nate]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 01:43:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-07-03T14:01:22.559Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*5rKu3NQK2WBmhNbWksf4Dw.jpeg" /></figure><p>Since its launch in 2014, the Sia network has been at the forefront of the decentralized storage space, offering private and cost-effective storage. Throughout its life, the primary software, siad, has been the cornerstone for both uploading files and providing storage. While significant advancements were made to the renter module, the host module remained relatively stagnant, limiting the network’s potential. The architecture of siad&#39;s host posed challenges for detecting issues and increasing performance. But now, with the beta release of hostd, storage providers can take advantage of a comprehensive set of enhancements and features that are fully compatible with the existing network.</p><p>With enhanced stability, faster upload and download speeds, improved resource management, and a user-friendly interface, hostd empowers storage providers to optimize their nodes and maximize their efficiency. By addressing the limitations of its predecessor, hostd enables providers to deliver a superior experience for consumers and drive the growth of the Sia network.</p><h3>Performance &amp; Stability</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*j7UC2YZ0PN6-a4S8N38Cvw.png" /><figcaption>performance comparisons (higher is better)</figcaption></figure><p>With hostd, the Sia network takes a leap forward in performance and stability. This new software has been designed to address and fix many of the performance-related issues and system lockups that were associated with the previous host software, siad. Major optimizations to the host’s hot path provides significantly increased performance and reduced system resource usage. Hosts should immediately notice much smoother operation and fewer interruptions in service.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*H89Dq385pzpoM7k0VBk7fQ.png" /><figcaption>RPC comparisons (lower is better)</figcaption></figure><p>The improvements in performance are evident when we compare average RPC times, expressed in milliseconds. Renters and hosts interact through Sia’s renter-host protocol. The append sector RPC is used to upload and store one 4MiB sector on the host, whereas the read sector RPC sends a sector from the host to the renter. Each RPC is now significantly faster, contributing to the performance boost.</p><p>As illustrated in the Performance Comparison graph, we observed significant improvements in both egress and ingress speeds. Specifically, egress speed (the speed at which the host sends data to renters) nearly doubled, and ingress speed (the speed at which the host receives and stores data) increased more than 16 times. These optimizations lead to a substantial acceleration in data processing, which in turn yields a more efficient and responsive network.</p><h3>Data Integrity</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NWVmLulYRQYMW-2KNdLvXQ.png" /><figcaption>hostd integrity check alerts</figcaption></figure><p>hostd introduces new data integrity tools, which empowers users to verify the completeness and accuracy of their stored data. These tools allow hosts to identify signs of data corruption early. A proactive approach enables timely resolution of issues, preventing them from escalating or affecting a wider range of data.</p><p>These tools not only increase the resilience of individual hosts, but also enhances the robustness and reliability of the whole Sia network. As we continue to refine and expand these tools, hosts can look forward to even more effective ways to manage and protect their data.</p><h3>Overhauled UI</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*B_ru1WUTsCsGLQpCtbESWQ.png" /><figcaption>hostd dashboard</figcaption></figure><p>In the past, siad was accessed via a command-line interface, siac. For a more user-friendly experience, desktop users could utilize Sia-UI and Sia Central’s Host Manager. However, there were no options available for server-based users to manage their hosts. With hostd, this concern has been addressed by including an embedded web interface. This web-based dashboard allows both local and remote management of hosts, making it easier for users to interact with and manage their storage nodes from anywhere.</p><h3>Metrics</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UgI5SL8nZspX_TBatjz_-g.png" /><figcaption>hostd metrics</figcaption></figure><p>When accessing the new UI, storage providers are immediately presented with various metric graphs, which enables users to track the performance of their host over time. These visualizations offer an easy-to-understand overview of how the host is performing.</p><p>The metric graphs present various crucial data points, such as bandwidth usage, data storage, pricing, among others. Providers can observe trends and patterns to identify areas where their host excels and where there may be room for improvement.</p><h3>Volume Management</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hw0BS661a5h46ZSy30_5FA.png" /><figcaption>hostd volumes</figcaption></figure><p>The volume management capabilities in hostd have been redesigned to provide greater control and convenience for storage providers. These features help manage how data is stored and transferred within the host system.</p><p>First, hostd introduces a feature to mark volumes as read-only. This means storage providers can designate certain volumes where new data cannot be written, allowing for more control over where data is being migrated within the software.</p><p>Second, hostd addresses issues with data migration that were present in siad. Specifically, hostd has resolved the issue of lockups that occurred when moving data from one volume to another. Now, storage providers can add, remove, or resize volumes without the system becoming unresponsive.</p><h3>Wallet</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-DKbcwr8Zh6-Li2exMS7MQ.png" /><figcaption>hostd wallet</figcaption></figure><p>hostd uses a new hot wallet using standard BIP-39 12-word seeds. By migrating all of our new apps to BIP-39, users can enjoy the convenience and interoperability provided by this widely accepted standard for mnemonic phrases.</p><p>In addition, we’ve introduced a comprehensive transaction list, a feature highly requested by hosts. Unlike in siad, where host contract payouts were not visible, hostd ensures these payouts are included in the transaction list. This feature improves the transparency of the wallet, enabling hosts to accurately track and audit their earnings over time.</p><p>The introduction of hostd is a major step forward for the Sia network, marking the beginning of a new era in performance and usability. By addressing the limitations of its predecessor, hostd not only optimizes the experience for storage providers — it also significantly contributes to the robustness of the network. With an ongoing commitment to further optimizing hostd and renterd, the Sia Foundation continues to push the boundaries of decentralized storage. As we continue to add and improve features, we look forward to seeing how our community of storage providers will leverage these advancements to deliver superior services and drive the future of decentralized storage.</p><p><strong>You can find the latest software at </strong><a href="https://sia.tech/software/hostd"><strong>https://sia.tech/software/hostd</strong></a></p><p><em>We conducted performance tests for this article on both siad and hostd to compare their capabilities. These tests were carried out on the same server running Ubuntu 20.04. In this setup, both softwares used the most common setup for Sia hosts: an NVMe drive to store metadata and a SATA HDD for data storage.</em></p><p><em>The benchmarking process consisted of ten tests for each software, uploading and downloading 1GiB of data in each test. For those interested in replicating these tests, the benchmarking utility is available on our GitHub: </em><a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/host-bench"><em>https://github.com/SiaFoundation/host-bench</em></a><em>.</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=871d7fea23de" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/introducing-hostd-871d7fea23de">Introducing hostd</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Sia, June 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-june-2023-b84a2843a71f?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b84a2843a71f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[storage]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 19:02:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-06-15T19:02:41.543Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8qev2964WikdIewPPY28JQ.png" /></figure><p>We’re back with the State of Sia, a monthly installment looking at development and team updates for The Sia Foundation.</p><p>The Sia Foundation takes a measured approach—one that has served us well in keeping the company strong and the network moving forward through a global pandemic and recession concerns. Bringing on three members from Skynet Labs during their shutdown was also a big deal for us. It resulted in a large increase in the team size, bringing with it effort to maintain the positive, people and platform-first culture we’re building.</p><p>It’s been a bit of time since then though, and we’re all in our new groove. It’s time to improve the Foundation’s and Sia’s capabilities yet again with the addition of our first 2023 employee, a <a href="https://siafoundation.homerun.co/developer-relations">Developer Relations expert</a>.</p><p>We’re in process with this and moving full-steam ahead, but if you’re think you’re the perfect fit for the role there’s still time to get your application in.</p><p>Beyond that, we’re moving ahead with some fantastic progress across the dev spectrum, and we should have something tangible for the hostd beta by the time the next one of these articles comes out.</p><p>Our quarterly report is coming up at the end of the month as well, so be on the lookout for some seasonal insight to Foundation operations. Let’s get to the good stuff.</p><h3>Development</h3><p>All public repos can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation">here</a>.</p><h3>renterd</h3><p>renterd will be our new stand-alone renter. The renterd repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd">here</a>, and the app is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/releases/tag/v0.1.0-beta">available in beta</a>.</p><ul><li>Fixed a bug where contracts wouldn’t expire for unusable hosts (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/347">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug that prevented workers from broadcasting renewal txns (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/382">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug where account balances weren’t synced due to the account being empty (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/377">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug where a contract wouldn’t renew if there is no valid pricetable (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/384">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug where long running uploads would fail due to host height gouging (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/364">Link</a>)</li><li>Revision number of contracts stored within the bus are now updated alongside contract spending metrics (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/369">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*YYyamtNU0Qsi08-zn4SLaA.png" /></figure><ul><li>worker endpoint /rhp/contracts/active was renamed to /rhp/contracts and returns all contracts now (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/351">Link</a>)</li><li>host_sectors table was dropped from the database (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/355">Link</a>)</li><li>migrations are now performed on all workers of a cluster in parallel (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/374">Link</a>)</li><li>hosts that announce themselves on private IP ranges will no longer be scanned by default (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/375">Link</a>)</li><li>bootstrapping renterd from an existing consensus.db won’t block the startup anymore and the API is available immediately (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/383">Link</a>)</li><li>wallet persistence was migrated to SQL DB (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/362">Link</a>)</li><li>Added the ability to set contract set and redundancy params in the worker API client (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/358">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed bug in private IP check (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/386">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*nGG2j2Nh59P3eDFvmEqFbQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added issue templates to repo (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/370">Link</a>)</li><li>Exposed database config through CLI (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/357">Link</a>)</li><li>Benchmarking and improving the performance of uploads — looking at a 4x improvement over the baseline so uploads are easily four times faster now and should scale pretty well after we rollout this fix. The progress can be followed here (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/390">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*hn8wmTt0hMkkEkRkf1CFgA.png" /></figure><h3>renterd ui</h3><p>The repos containing the various UIs being worked on can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web">here</a>. A full detailed changelog can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/releases">here</a>.</p><ul><li>The copy authenticated URL toast is now properly formatted (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/44d74f3d210f6a2958b3cbe6e59d83b59adb1203">Link</a>)</li><li>Contract timelines and other features based on block height now use estimated block height for current height until synced (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>The delete file confirmation now uses a red button (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/6d8bde8a601d8e4f833b6198f9324bd245fd4624">Link</a>)</li><li>Core features are now immediately accessible without waiting for blockchain sync to complete (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>Hovering over the Sia logo now triggers a popover that shows daemon info and sync status (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>Deleting a file now requires confirmation (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/c7d22889a0d1fb7e4a092378c998730cf4dcff0b">Link</a>)</li><li>Configuration tabs now include more specific validation errors and feedback (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/fef9e828f7fee6d217580e574f00c76ed7048501">Link</a>)</li><li>Configuration now shows average network prices based off Sia Central data (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/017c75416e7c661d7e387a4a1cbbbd4a219dc9d5">Link</a>)</li><li>The contracts feature has been updated to use the new endpoint (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/eef3a74193b2df7b0150857f373bf712fb5380f7">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>hostd</h3><p>hostd is the app you’ll be using to rent out your excess storage space to the Sia network. The hostd repo is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd">public</a>, with a beta coming soon.</p><ul><li>Created setup guides for Linux, macOS, and Windows (<a href="https://docs.sia.tech/hosting/hostd/setup-guides">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*M5yvmNmL-_1pM0QpG9ACSg.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added status to volume (ready, resizing, removing) to enable tracking the current state of the volume.</li><li>Fixed an issue with force removing a volume failing when the volume file is missing.</li><li>Fixed an issue with the a contract’s reject lifecycle action triggering every block</li><li>Fixed issues with settings endpoint when patching DDNS options</li><li>Fixed an error with /system/dir?path=~ when the user does not have a home directory.</li><li>Fixed an issue where RHP3 account refunds would trigger max account balance error. Fixes an issue when using contract payments.</li><li>Hid 0 H intermediary transactions from the wallet. Intermediary transactions do not affect the wallet and add bloat to the transaction list.</li><li>Added “Subtract Fee” param to /wallet/send endpoint. This allows the user to subtract the transaction fee from the send amount, useful when sending the entire wallet balance.</li><li>Added handling for confusing AWS Route53 error messages</li><li>Added special handling in /system/dir for Windows paths. / or \ will now return used drive letters.</li><li>Added error field to contract integrity check. Errors were only available in the log, but now can be seen in the API response.</li><li>Finished API documentation (<a href="https://api.sia.tech/hostd">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2gKizYyl9WwxQ5r0xT1csw.png" /></figure><h3>hostd ui</h3><p>A full detailed changelog can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/releases">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Directory navigation in the volume creation dialog now works properly when navigating up to the root drive (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/d32ffbe44e04f8f8ff021721e51e470347ca2fd8">Link</a>)</li><li>Metrics charts now properly show the final data point (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7900664ef2bde6d50bf99f7ae80f3ef35e6d8a7e">Link</a>)</li><li>New directories can now be created directly from the volume creation dialog directory selection tool (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/2994f8f472175ab3df327fbfe3eb1b54478738b0">Link</a>)</li><li>Dynamic DNS configuration errors are now displayed in full (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/08e616b1dcf4d46ccdd4fa81a7748e999260e085">Link</a>)</li><li>Price settings are no longer described as “minimum” (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7299f003d2634296a5ea92ce80dd93dc262c5da1">Link</a>)</li><li>Host announcement transactions now show up labeled as such in the transaction list (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/8bae49598f4dac35eecf42fbb6d2c5112859a64c">Link</a>)</li><li>Volumes view and create now available from the command palette (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/14fd2ef467f286f9208d015cb22f255393d5e3e6">Link</a>)</li><li>Contract total usage sum now no longer includes risked collateral (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/21b582c893def2088a984fad55a16dd33146c462">Link</a>)</li><li>Contract timelines and other features based on block height now use estimated block height for current height until synced (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>Core features are now immediately accessible without waiting for blockchain sync to complete (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>Hovering over the Sia logo now triggers a popover that shows daemon info and sync status (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/1a482f2d368a274929db4ab41d50b1ebd14137a5">Link</a>)</li><li>The displayed wallet balance is now spendable+unconfirmed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/eb0cd0da7586c076e47bae77dbb9ec95caf3db88">Link</a>)</li><li>The volume delete dialog now resets when it is closed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/6d8bde8a601d8e4f833b6198f9324bd245fd4624">Link</a>)</li><li>Risked collateral is now next to locked collateral in the contracts table (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/21b582c893def2088a984fad55a16dd33146c462">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>jape</h3><p>jape is what we use to check that the API routes between client/server are consistent.</p><ul><li>Added support for HTTP PATCH requests (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/jape/pull/11">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>ledger</h3><ul><li>Porting to Stax (<a href="https://github.com/siafoundation/app-sia-x/pull/2">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixes after Ledger’s review (<a href="https://github.com/siafoundation/app-sia-x/pull/3">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>That’s all folks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/710/1*UUUV6hsBIfO7qYzmUUJ96w.jpeg" /></figure><p>We’re enjoying the beginning of summer and taking steps towards building a stronger Foundation and a better Sia.</p><p>Until next time!</p><p><a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>, <a href="mailto:hello@sia.tech">Email</a></p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b84a2843a71f" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-june-2023-b84a2843a71f">The State of Sia, June 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Sia, May 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-may-2023-bc2089bc14f1?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/bc2089bc14f1</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[storage]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ssi]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 15:32:20 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-05-16T15:32:20.529Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*XPZZ7414yrvd2ipOJZ8axA.png" /></figure><p>We’re back with the State of Sia, a monthly installment looking at development and team updates for The Sia Foundation.</p><p>Spring has sprung for the Sia team. We’ve been monitoring the release of the renterd beta in our <a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a> and are finding that not only do people really like the new software, they <em>really love</em> the new UI. Alex’s part-facelift, part-reconstructive surgery has done wonders for Sia after being neglected for quite literally years in the form of our previous gen Sia-UI. It’s great to see our software have a friendly new face, and we’ll be working hard on documentation for it in the weeks to come.</p><p>We’ve created a new category on the forums for <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/c/foundation/proposal-ideas/">Proposal Ideas</a>. If you have an idea for a project you think could be valuable to the Sia ecosystem or uses Sia in an important way, we’d love to hear it! All forum users can vote on ideas they like, and the best-voted ideas may get turned into grants of their own. In fact, we just received our first <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-siashare/">grant proposal</a> based off of one of these ideas.</p><p>The Foundation’s <a href="https://sia.tech/transparency/2023-q1.pdf">Q1 2023 report</a> is now available, and we just published the latest <a href="https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-april-2023-the-six-month-check-in-d9c3404d7441">Grants Update blog post</a>. The latter has a quick rundown of numbers and projects to commemorate six months!</p><p>For our final bit of “pre-good stuff” exposition, the Sia team attended the MIT Bitcoin expo, an event that we’ve sponsored for quite a few years now. It was great to catch up with the local community, talk with users, and judge hackathon participants. Congrats to the winners!</p><p>And now, on with the show.</p><h3>Development</h3><p>All public repos can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation">here</a>.</p><h3>renterd</h3><p>renterd will be our new stand-alone renter. The renterd repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd">here</a>, and the app is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/releases/tag/v0.1.0-beta">available in beta</a>.</p><ul><li>Added Zen Testnet publish workflow. Automatically builds a Docker image and binaries for use with the Zen Testnet (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/256">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an underflow when computing health for “lost” files (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/266">Link</a>)</li><li>Set content-type header when serving objects (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/292">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed range requests for downloads (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/279">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed issue where renterd would potentially form multiple contracts with the same host (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/276">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*yX3e-ENUpXy0M24814pPDg.png" /></figure><ul><li>Fixed a rare panic related to contract locking (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/307">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where downloads would randomly return corrupted data (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/303">Link</a>)</li><li>Upgraded uploads to use rhpv3 protocol instead of rhpv2 (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/320">Link</a>)</li><li>Migrate renewals to use rhpv3 protocol instead of rhpv2 (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/264">Link</a>)</li><li>Contracts will only become unusable for uploads if they haven’t renewed by the start of the second half of the renew window (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/267">Link</a>)</li><li>Reduced the prefix length for IPv6 addresses used to geographically distribute hosts we form contracts with (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/319">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed bug in host pruning (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/272">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed bug in contract archival (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/297">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/300">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed bug in price table updates (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/297">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed various panics (host scoring) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/305">Link</a>)</li><li>Improved contractor performance (most notably fetching revisions happens in parallel now — big speed improvement there) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/299">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*tDkVIOQmyKIAcabpNbYAeQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added validation to autopilot configuration (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/302">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>renterd-benchmark</h3><ul><li>Added parallel upload benchmarking tools to the renterd benchmarking tool (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd-benchmark">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3><strong>hostd</strong></h3><p>hostd is the app you’ll be using to rent out your excess storage space to the Sia network. The hostd repo is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd">public</a>.</p><ul><li>Added RHP3 websocket handler and SSL certificate management. Enables interacting with hosts directly from web browsers (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/6eae867e57993bfbcf3b2596ed6557d41689aa95">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NkXOcJ-Rxk312DANNrC0JQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added API endpoints for querying host logs. Logs can now be queried and filtered through the API. Useful for remote setups (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/9d6cb5d66b58b17aa31c8fe74d47915dbc42085d">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed missing proofs for append, delete, swap and read instructions (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/5ec7cfcb1d54a94bca3fedc5a151619abe9076c0">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed an issue where rejected contracts would continue to be checked every block (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/abd8ea79e0e74d12251254d8b419cc648abd574a">Link</a>)</li><li>Added DynDNS to host settings, added update flow, and endpoints (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/3e28a6fbe90149b87b0c56ef44962463c94f59b8">Link</a>)</li><li>Added pricing to metrics. This will let hosts track pricing changes over time (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/0d570a339fb11a3a172228ec3a74043a3edc0b56">Link</a>)</li><li>Expose the contract resolution height. This will enable the UI to display the payout height for each contract (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/afd54c6b3c3961822558e79b4169f56a2bcb351c">Link</a>)</li><li>Added filesystem endpoints for exposing directories and disk sizes for remote management (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/be58a937f6f33b8782eaf69632f95467acb5cacc">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/47d17530825788a17ed52b29c4914cfdc8400ff2">Link</a>)</li><li>Added PriceTableValidity to the host settings (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/41">Link</a>)</li><li>Added ephemeral account settings to the host settings (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/pull/42">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>core</h3><p>The core repo is public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Added “MidStates” to core. This reifies an important concept in consensus code, making validation and application code more powerful and easier to understand (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/107">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*NSO22vSFxWGxnKNR4Cvq9Q.png" /></figure><ul><li>Implemented core transaction pool. The transaction pool is a key component of any blockchain system, and will be used by all core-based Sia node software. Compared to siad, we took a slightly different approach in core by merging the pool with the chain management code (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/108">Link</a>)</li><li>Added tests for the consensus code in v1 core: (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/99">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/100">Link</a>). Basically checking that bad transactions are rejected (inputs &gt; outputs, double spends, invalid contracts, etc).</li></ul><h3>walletd</h3><p>walletd will be Sia’s new stand-alone wallet app.</p><ul><li>We now have a fully-functionality core-based Sia wallet that can connect to peers, sync the chain, and send and receive siacoins. The next step is to implement a UI around the walletd server. We’ll aim to get an alpha version out in May.</li></ul><h3>ledger sia-x</h3><ul><li>We’ve been working on porting the existing Ledger app to the new Ledger Stax (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/app-sia-x/commits/stax-port">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2nrmXmKdj--YyvT-B-PXFA.png" /></figure><h3>web</h3><p>The following work might be done on renterd or hostd’s UI, the website, or other web-adjacent repos. Check the links, and the repos containing the various UIs being worked on can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web">here</a>.</p><ul><li>The files explorer now shows the total size of directories (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/ad4f096b70f1c4dabd046c8ea77a567cab218dde">Link</a>)</li><li>The sync screen now shows the correct network block height when using the Zen testnet (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/d746281db2789287b929e44acd8b73b83510246f">Link</a>)</li><li>The unlock form now times out after 5s and shows a new ‘Error, daemon did not respond’ error — this occurs when the wallet is re-indexing (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/d746281db2789287b929e44acd8b73b83510246f">Link</a>)</li><li>The hosts explorer column state icons are now more clear, some columns now use a gray negative or non-initialized state (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/5059a85646fd835f06da86267c6d1ebca752b630">Link</a>)</li><li>The network block height is now estimated. renterd no longer uses SiaStats for anything so the 3rd party data privacy toggle has also been removed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/d746281db2789287b929e44acd8b73b83510246f">Link</a>)</li><li>The file menu now provides “Copy URL”, and “Copy authenticated URL” functions (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>The files copy metadata option is now disabled in the data is unavailable or fetching (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>The wallet sparklines have been temporarily hidden until we have support for all inflow/outflow events such as returned allowance (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>The files feature now supports UTF-8 directory and file names (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/ad4f096b70f1c4dabd046c8ea77a567cab218dde">Link</a>)</li><li>The home dashboard now shows a variety of metrics and allows changing the data time range (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7b0a75c824b6dbbeda00b12d2893d0107bf55c33">Link</a>)</li><li>Charts now supports grouping stats by category, such as hostd earned and potential revenue (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>The contracts explorer now allows filtering on status and contract ID, these are also accessible via the global ⌘K palette (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/12d206f8d4d07e66bf37ff73c12dda4e5df661f9">Link</a>)</li><li>The contracts explorer now features columns for a contract timeline, siacoin usage by type, data size, and more (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/12d206f8d4d07e66bf37ff73c12dda4e5df661f9">Link</a>)</li><li>The contracts explorer now supports view column configuration and sorting by status and timeline (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/12d206f8d4d07e66bf37ff73c12dda4e5df661f9">Link</a>)</li><li>The sync screen now shows the correct network block height when using the Zen testnet (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/ddebbb12b8cf2267ed24434017bb8c2eaeed152c">Link</a>)</li><li>Charts now have loading states (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>Button now has a text color override prop (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7b0a75c824b6dbbeda00b12d2893d0107bf55c33">Link</a>)</li><li>ChartXY now shows the tooltip for zero values (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7b0a75c824b6dbbeda00b12d2893d0107bf55c33">Link</a>)</li><li>Menu item disabled states have been improved (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>ChartXY now supports custom data labels (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7b0a75c824b6dbbeda00b12d2893d0107bf55c33">Link</a>)</li><li>Select now supports a custom icon (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/7b0a75c824b6dbbeda00b12d2893d0107bf55c33">Link</a>)</li><li>The toast API has been extended to support generic React components (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>Toasts now use proper default styling when used in apps (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/879ee131dd5f5bad421ee411fcde96135b1ddb4a">Link</a>)</li><li>The autopilot target price default value calculation has been corrected (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/13a988255d446b3cdce77ffef106689eb0d9ab3c">Link</a>)</li><li>Siacoin inputs are now easier to use, especially when entering and editing decimal values (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/13a988255d446b3cdce77ffef106689eb0d9ab3c">Link</a>)</li><li>The txpool and wallet transaction lists now show the specific type of transaction (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/842ffbee0949c63f22a498fa85dc0ffd841a2b14">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed a bug in the send siacoin transaction flow (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/842ffbee0949c63f22a498fa85dc0ffd841a2b14">Link</a>)</li><li>Host and contract explorer view menus now allow toggling column visibility by group (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/72ab6fe9e0d5c320dc7b33b12f40c62f64ec1685">Link</a>)</li><li>The host explorer view menu now allows toggling column visibility by group (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/72ab6fe9e0d5c320dc7b33b12f40c62f64ec1685">Link</a>)</li><li>Autopilot estimates are now accurately labeled with TiB units (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/30493f482027ad10238577109e49ceb17bf86112">Link</a>)</li><li>renterd now has proper page titles (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/8510fc86628bb29a2fa5b2a0948fefc15ea5afc0">Link</a>)</li><li>The host menu now provides an option to trigger a manual rescan (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/2a0a7145f834ced2bb42bb851a713a2a764b852e">Link</a>)</li><li>Autopilot and config features now show any input errors (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/30493f482027ad10238577109e49ceb17bf86112">Link</a>)</li><li>Host and contract tables now show 50 items per page (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/72ab6fe9e0d5c320dc7b33b12f40c62f64ec1685">Link</a>)</li><li>The renterd sidenav no longer flickers when changing tabs (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/242937b5d25d99330b79e6ae869bacbc48c3a854">Link</a>)</li><li>The autopilot and configuration features now have an option to reset all changes (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/13a988255d446b3cdce77ffef106689eb0d9ab3c">Link</a>)</li><li>The gouging max storage price setting is now entered as a value per TiB per month, and properly stored a value per byte per block (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/13a988255d446b3cdce77ffef106689eb0d9ab3c">Link</a>)</li><li>The host explorer table now includes columns for the host price table and host settings (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/72ab6fe9e0d5c320dc7b33b12f40c62f64ec1685">Link</a>)</li><li>Autopilot feature is now enabled properly (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web/commit/3abd60c73d62a6f8dc47508691f316a5cfc4cfb1">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>workshop</h3><ul><li>Organized and created a new Sia workshop and documentation (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/wiki/Workshop">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*UcXmsrz8Qq_m60bxGzfkKw.png" /></figure><h3>That’s all folks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/710/1*UUUV6hsBIfO7qYzmUUJ96w.jpeg" /></figure><p>Thanks for another great month! We’ll be back in a few weeks as we really get into summer and bring big new updates to our host of apps.</p><p>Until next time!</p><p><a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>, <a href="mailto:hello@sia.tech">Email</a></p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=bc2089bc14f1" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-may-2023-bc2089bc14f1">The State of Sia, May 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grants Program Update, April 2023 — The Six Month Check-In]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-april-2023-the-six-month-check-in-d9c3404d7441?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/d9c3404d7441</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[grants-for-nonprofit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 18:41:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-04-27T18:41:01.570Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3>Grants Program Update, April 2023 — The Six Month Check-In</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*EEWPF38lIaq9QUrL0dbwDA.png" /></figure><p>The Sia Foundation has grant funding available for community contributors! The Grants Program was created to fund research, development, developer tools, and anything else that will support and further our mission of user-owned data while enriching the Sia ecosystem.</p><p>Just design a proposal that meets our requirements, submit to our forums, and wait for review by our grants committee. If your grant gets approved, you’re on your way to creating the next great project on the Sia storage network.</p><p>Check out <a href="https://sia.tech/grants">our site</a> for more info.</p><h3>The Current State of Grants</h3><p>The Grants Program was <a href="https://blog.sia.tech/announcing-the-sia-foundations-grants-program-f6327847b88a">launched in October 2022</a>, making April the half-year anniversary of a program that has surprised and delighted us both in terms of the quantity and quality of submissions we’ve received.</p><p>We’ve reviewed 18 grant proposals to date and have approved 10 of them, with projects including ecosystem research, L2 platforms, news aggregators, media streaming, and more. The grant funds disbursed are allowing community members, individuals, and small teams the opportunity to contribute to Sia in new and exciting ways.</p><h4>Curated ideas</h4><p>There’s projects that we don’t have the time or desire to pursue, or haven’t even considered ourselves. The Grants Program is an incredible way for us to use our resources to still support them and materially enhance Sia.</p><p>To this end, we’ve created a new category in our forum called <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/c/foundation/proposal-ideas/">Proposal Ideas</a>. As the name implies, you can suggest an idea that you’d like to see <em>someone else</em> put together a grant proposal for — something that will benefit the Sia network and its users. This category also allows voting, so you can help the best ideas rise to the top. We’ve begun adding some of our favorite ideas to this category, so head on over and add yours too. You could give a dev their next big idea.</p><h4>Progress makes perfect</h4><p>Our first grant was completed with <a href="https://app.alphaday.com/b/f95ea2ba4c9af7b29d7d16881aa63cde">Alphaday</a>, a news and on-chain data aggregator. The OG grant squad from Q4 of last year is progressing well, with <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-lume-web/229/41">Lume</a>, <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-fabstir/238/27">Fabstir</a>, and <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-sia-satellite/240/18">Sia Satellite</a> all moving along and in some cases nearing completion.</p><p>Messari just released the first of their <a href="https://messari.io/report/state-of-sia-q1-2023">Sia research reports</a>, and our latest grant approvals are all detailed below!</p><h4>New reviews</h4><p>Since the last update, we’ve approved four new grants: TwikkL, Autify Network, SiaFrench, and the S5 network. We’ve also rejected one called SiaFlow. Let’s take a look at each.</p><h3>TwikkL</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-twikkl/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A decentralized video-sharing platform that utilizes blockchain technology and Sia storage network to provide a censorship-free and transparent environment for users to share and stream videos.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>The TwikkL team was very patient with us — we first requested an update to their proposal, and then that proposal came in just a little late so we pushed back review a couple times.</p><p>Despite the wait, TwikkL was approved after providing clarity on their timeline, abuse handling, risks, and budget justification.</p><h3>S5</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-s5-network-and-apps/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A content-addressed storage network designed and built from the ground up to enable new decentralized apps and websites with significant improvements compared to their centralized counterparts.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>Redsolver has been working on S5 as a community member for a while, so the committee was well-aware of its potential. As a <em>committee</em> member, Redsolver of course recused himself from the approval process as per committee rules.</p><p>S5 has a ton of potential, and we’re incredibly excited to see how it develops.</p><h3>Autify Network</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-autify-network/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A supply chain management platform that wants to store their images/product metadata on Sia/Filebase.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>After kicking it back for amendments, the Autify team responded with a proposal worthy of approval. The committee was pleased to see their commitment to open-source the project under the AGPL license, a more thoughtful list of risks, and more information regarding budget concerns.</p><h3>SiaFrench</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-siafrench/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A project to develop an API framework and docs for English and French.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>The committee requested that the SiaFrench team refine their initial proposal, and drop other aspects like a community management initiative entirely. The committee was pleased to see the team filter the scope of the proposal to just the API work, and is hopeful that this project will help diversify the tools available to the Sia community.</p><h3>SiaFlow</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-siaflow/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>SiaFlow provides a comprehensive platform that delivers various insights and metrics to track the activities and development of the Sia ecosystem and its associated open-source projects.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Rejected</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>While the committee appreciated this proposal, they decided to reject it. They cited the number of other places the project had been submitted for grant funds, the likelihood of continued maintenance, and the usefulness to the community.</p><h3>Coming Next</h3><p>We encourage the community to provide their feedback and ask questions on the <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/">Sia Forum</a>! Community contribution and input is the best way to push proposals and projects to the next level.</p><p>You can see the list of all proposals <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/c/foundation/grants/">here</a>, and our proposal requirements <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/about-the-grants-category/">here</a>. See you next month!</p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=d9c3404d7441" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-april-2023-the-six-month-check-in-d9c3404d7441">Grants Program Update, April 2023 — The Six Month Check-In</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Sia, April 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-april-2023-b829036dc8f?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/b829036dc8f</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[ssi]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[storage]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 16:35:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-04-05T16:37:00.919Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*kuga5l3H6VLUyE03d7stqg.png" /></figure><p>We’re back with the State of Sia, a monthly installment looking at development and team updates for The Sia Foundation.</p><p>And so ends the first quarter of 2023. In a feat of being Technically Correct, we have indeed released the renterd <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/releases/tag/v0.1.0-beta">beta</a> that we’ve been chatting about for a while, right on time in the late hours of March 31st :)</p><p>Featuring new architecture that the dev team has been working incredibly hard on, and a beautiful re-imagined UI/UX from Alex, this is our first step towards the future of the Foundation. Our newly-built apps for renting, hosting, and wallet functions will continue to march towards full releases. The plan right now is to have a hostd beta, and a renterd full release, in the coming months.</p><p>We can’t wait for you to try them out.</p><p>Switching gears, a recent development affecting the Sia ecosystem was the announcement from Bittrex that they are shutting down US operations, with the last full day to withdraw your funds being April 29, 2023. We’ve put together a brief guide for navigating this, as well as what it means for the broader Sia network, <a href="https://blog.sia.tech/psa-bittrex-is-shutting-down-5a6d9e8df44a">here</a>.</p><p>Finally, while we mention this later I want to call something out right now. We’ve updated sia.tech with a new roadmap for the Foundation’s work. This is a mid to high level look at core Sia development, both current and future. It focuses on the big projects we’re working on, what we’ve got planned next, and includes an activity feed from all of our public repos.</p><p>It will be updated at least once a quarter to reflect changes in our priorities or to recognize significant accomplishments. This roadmap is important for a few reasons — it’s something easy to point new users, potential partners, and exchanges to. The activity feed gives a quick look at development that might otherwise fly under the radar. And it just looks really cool. Check it out over at <a href="https://sia.tech/roadmap">sia.tech/roadmap</a>.</p><p>I was personally really impressed with how quickly we put this together. What started out as a tentative request in an informal meeting turned into something real, and significant, in less than two weeks. And that’s with a whole bunch of other important things going on.</p><p>That’ll do it for me, let’s get on to the good stuff.</p><h3>Development</h3><p>All public repos can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation">here</a>.</p><h3>renterd</h3><p>renterd will be our new stand-alone renter. The renterd repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd">here</a>, and the app is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/releases/tag/v0.1.0-beta">available in beta</a>.</p><ul><li>Profiled and benchmarked the upload and download performance in renterd. A new benchmarking tool was written for this purpose (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd-benchmark">Link</a>)</li><li>Autopilot can be configured with multiple workers used for maintenance (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/175">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Mn1omTR9EajsjqOWN4O-8Q.png" /></figure><ul><li>Tracking more contract info (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/179">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/181">Link</a>)</li><li>Improved object search endpoints (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/192">Link</a>)</li><li>Calculated transaction outflow (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/227">Link</a>)</li><li>Added endpoint for listing all contract sets (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/193">Link</a>)</li><li>Host prices are taken into account when scoring them (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/199">Link</a>)</li><li>Added Autopilot endpoints to fetch host info including their score (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/204">Link</a>)</li><li>Added testnet support via build flag (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/225">Link</a>)</li><li>Improved general working condition of the worker and autopilot by improving logging and fixing some small bugs (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/201">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/245">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/198">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/236">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/182">Link</a>)</li><li>Favour fast hosts when downloading (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/213">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed docker container not shutting down cleanly (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/174">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed files becoming unhealthy when corresponding contract is renewed (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/176">Link</a>)</li><li>Added a retry when applying failed db transactions (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/184">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>renterd ui</h3><p>The repos containing the various UIs being worked on can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/web">here</a>.</p><ul><li>The configuration settings now include host block height leeway.</li><li>renterd now has a syncing flow that shows blockchain sync progress and allows the user to manually connect more peers and manage settings.</li><li>The Files breadcrumb nav now scrolls to show the working directory when necessary.</li><li>Host explorer now includes a block status column and the hover tooltip explains how each list contributed to being blocked or not.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_EA6Qzh_GgCohkHBUajmIA.png" /></figure><ul><li>Apps now have embed specific build flags, embedded apps do not show a server field at login.</li><li>The host explorer now supports filtering hosts by block status and address.</li><li>The global command menu now has empty states.</li><li>Contract spending is now displayed as a negative value.</li><li>The file health indicator now shows a breakdown of shards per slab on hover.</li><li>Data loading and filtering states have been refined across all features.</li><li>The file explorer now lists parent directory for traversing up a level.</li><li>The host explorer now features quick filters and actions for each host row.</li><li>Contracts, hosts, and files tables now include an error state.</li><li>Files now show their current health based on how many data shards have active contracts.</li><li>The contracts explorer now supports filtering by address and public key.</li><li>renterd now supports searching for files, access the feature from the Files actions menu or through the global command menu.</li><li>The files explorer now supports navigation, directory creation, file deletion, and more.</li><li>File paths are now linkable and reflected in the app URL.</li><li>The blocklist manager now suggests adding well-known spam addresses to blocklist and shows whether renterd has any active contracts with hosts matching these addresses.</li><li>The hosts feature now shows autopilot score and score breakdown columns.</li><li>The gouging config now includes min max collateral.</li><li>The files feature now has a view configuration menu.</li><li>The apps are now built into Go modules exposing static assets as an embed.FS.</li><li>The hosts feature now shows whether autopilot considers the host usable based on the scoring criteria. If the host is unusable, the reasons are listed.</li><li>Fixed an issue where siacoin config values were being sent as decimal strings.</li><li>Host, contract, and file explorer action menus are now all accessed via an icon on the far left of each row.</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/978/1*aFyeAfl8w652AoAcNdhcHQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>The hosts feature now allows filtering to hosts with active contracts.</li><li>renterd now supports allowlist and blocklist management, accessible from the global command menu or the hosts page.</li><li>All autopilot features are now disabled and hidden if renterd is running with autopilot disabled.</li><li>The contract timeline now shows points for contract revisions and proofs.</li><li>Fix a z-index Safari bug that would clip the action dropdown in the AppLayout.</li><li>PaginatorUnknownTotal now displays correct last page values.</li><li>The Table components column sizing has been improved.</li><li>Lock and sync screens now remember and redirect back to the previous page.</li></ul><h3>hostd</h3><p>hostd is the app you’ll be using to rent out your excess storage space to the Sia network. The hostd repo is <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd">public</a>.</p><ul><li>Added sign and notarize to publish workflow so macOS users can run binaries (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/244b22a75490ffa965ead90ca8279552a7e7d26c">Link</a>)</li><li>Added an OpenAPI spec so users can generate API clients in any language (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/92d5ca4d116f6da7633b5d4b3caf3716f7953bc9">Link</a>)</li><li>Separated the host and wallet private keys to make it possible for hosts to migrate from siad (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/f514fbfa23aedb4196c0e8d82b93c645ea43df5d">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/678/1*fDoYd6qS91YqiPMid2rAAw.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added a &quot;rejected&quot; status to contracts that do not make it on chain (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/daef7d6b9580712fa6e34d6cb0cc06bb662a8aac">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/8c3501961b5d34ec14f5d266ee15399b38831d21">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed performance issues in volume manager when dealing with large volumes (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/0b12b0495521f9241c6b6d9dcf96e8364816a117">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/e1aa052b1d9e0332425a025ab69f7760e2c8716f">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/f2a92a340cbd2f6e743da0a4da338f82cdf09fce">Link</a>)</li><li>Added debug logging for slow queries, this will make it easier to track down performance bottlenecks (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/2c5bed452c943f9d1399f43589150160ac8a7d92">Link</a>)</li><li>Added filtering to the contracts endpoint (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/hostd/commit/060feab852f6e7639b8863ae6b99a80f1c26993b">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>core</h3><p>The core repo is public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Added network parameterization. This allows us to specify different network parameters, such as the target block time, without having to recompile the entire program as in siad (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/98">Link</a>)</li><li>Added gateway protocol support. This is a first step towards replacing the siad gateway module; much of the remaining code is already written, but uncommitted. renterd, hostd, and walletd will make use of this code to communicate with other Sia nodes (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/101">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*KtoscL6FTHpZEfHyVNvc3A.png" /></figure><ul><li>Added tests for the consensus code in v1 core. These basically check that bad transactions are rejected (inputs &gt; outputs, double spends, invalid contracts, etc) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/99">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/100">Link</a>)</li><li>Added the RHP3 renew RPC protocol objects (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/103">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>website</h3><ul><li>The website now features the Sia Foundation’s new roadmap (<a href="https://sia.tech/roadmap">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*FsDaur0MGVt-4gpzIVlI5A.png" /></figure><ul><li>The website now features a feed of GitHub development activity (<a href="https://sia.tech/activity">Link</a>)</li><li>Added docs.sia.tech to the site map and adjusted categorization.</li></ul><h3>Ledger</h3><ul><li>Worked on porting the existing Ledger app to the new Ledger Stax (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/app-sia-x/commits/stax-port">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>That’s all folks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/710/1*UUUV6hsBIfO7qYzmUUJ96w.jpeg" /></figure><p>This was a big update. I’m sure next time around we’ll have more to say about the renterd beta, and the progress we’ve made towards the rest of our app suite. April also takes us to MIT Bitcoin, so we’ll have a recap of all the action from Boston.</p><p>Until next time!</p><p><a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>, <a href="mailto:hello@sia.tech">Email</a></p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=b829036dc8f" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-april-2023-b829036dc8f">The State of Sia, April 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PSA: Bittrex is shutting down US operations]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/psa-bittrex-is-shutting-down-5a6d9e8df44a?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/5a6d9e8df44a</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[bittrex]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cryptocurrency]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[exchange]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 19:40:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-04-04T19:42:47.056Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*-UEODuJp38AEFDkL3Mq7ug.png" /></figure><p>Last Friday, Bittrex announced that they will be shutting down US operations effective April 30, 2023 at 12PM PDT/3PM EDT.</p><h3>First things first</h3><p>If you hold Siacoins, any other cryptocurrency, or any fiat in your Bittrex wallet you need to move those funds out to a safe account that you control. I never miss an opportunity to remind folks — not your keys, not your crypto. Keeping cryptocurrency in an exchange wallet is one of the easiest ways to lose it. Fortunately, Bittrex has provided ample time for you to transfer your funds, so make use of this opportunity.</p><h3>A little closer to home</h3><p>Now that that’s out of the way, I’d like to talk about how this affects The Sia Foundation and our users.</p><p>The loss of Bittrex is an unfortunate event for Sia users in the United States. Bittrex provided a reliable way to get Siacoins so users could use them for their purpose of purchasing and renting storage on the Sia network. It was also the second largest exchange for trading Siacoins by daily volume, so a not-insignificant amount of users will be affected.<br> <br>Fortunately, Kraken is still available for US users. Kraken is consistently the most-used US exchange for trading Siacoins by daily volume, and has been a reputable resource for the community. For now, we recommend that Sia users in the US create a Kraken account for acquiring Siacoins to rent storage.</p><p>The Foundation is also looking into options to expand the footprint of US exchanges that offer Siacoins. We’ll have more info on this as it becomes available.</p><h3>Links and info</h3><p>Learn how to set up our <a href="https://docs.sia.tech/your-sia-wallet/sia-ui-faqs/how-to-make-a-new-wallet-in-sia-ui">official Sia wallet</a>, and follow these steps to <a href="https://docs.sia.tech/your-sia-wallet/how-to-make-a-sia-address">make an address</a> to transfer your Siacoins over.</p><p>A full timeline of the Bittrex shutdown can be found <a href="https://bittrex.zendesk.com/hc/en-us/articles/10080271948701">here</a>.</p><p>For any other questions, please reach out in our <a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>.</p><p><em>Sia is a blockchain-based storage network that allows users to store their files in a fully decentralized way that is safer and less expensive than traditional centralized options.</em></p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=5a6d9e8df44a" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/psa-bittrex-is-shutting-down-5a6d9e8df44a">PSA: Bittrex is shutting down US operations</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Grants Program Update, March 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-march-2023-1e0d1cd9c74c?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/1e0d1cd9c74c</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[blockchain]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[grants-for-nonprofit]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 17:58:53 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-03-14T17:58:53.797Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*V8rBjhg4AKS_tC3fI4kalg.png" /></figure><p>The Sia Foundation has grant funding available for community contributors! The Grants Program was created to fund research, development, developer tools, and anything else that will support and further our mission of user-owned data while enriching the Sia ecosystem.</p><p>Just design a proposal that meets our requirements, submit to our forums, and wait for review by our grants committee. If your grant gets approved, you’re on your way to creating the next great project on the Sia storage network.</p><p>Check out <a href="https://sia.tech/grants">our site</a> for more info.</p><h3>The Current State of Grants</h3><p>The committee reviewed one new grant and checked in on the progress reports from all our existing grantees. We’ve also got another new one to take a look at, which arrived just late enough for the committee to need additional time to review.</p><h3>New Proposal: Rocket Web3 Game</h3><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/technical-grant-application-web3-game-rocket-rocket/">Link</a></p><h4>What is it?</h4><p>A simple space game with a crypto marketplace and earnings system.</p><h4>Grant Status</h4><p>Not approved</p><h4>Updates</h4><p>Our first game idea had an interesting premise, but a lacking proposal. While the committee is open to reconsidering, the committee needed to better understand how Sia would be integrated, better budget justification, and a bit more detailed breakdown of the timeline and goals.</p><h3>Progress Reports</h3><p>When you accept a grant, you commit to update the Foundation and community once a month with a progress report detailing your work done, milestones you’ve met, and what you’ll work on next. Here’s a quick recap of some of the latest progress reports we’ve received from previous grantees.</p><h4>Fabstir</h4><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-fabstir/238/24">Link</a></p><ul><li>Set up local MiniKubes test media player/transcoder infrastructures.</li><li>Successfully uploaded a video to the media player cluster, which was then uploaded to S5.</li><li>Added authorization token functionality to the tus_client Rust native code, enabling Redsolver’s code snippet to upload files with authorization.</li></ul><h4>Alphaday</h4><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/alphaday-is-a-powerful-crypto-workflow-aggregator-that-pulls-in-news-on-chain-data-social-media-web3-services-and-much-more-into-one-customizable-ui/251/9">Link</a></p><p>Alphaday is 99% complete, and the committee has been seeing internal versions prior to release. This will likely be our first fully complete grant.</p><h4>Lume Web</h4><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-lume-web/229/36">Link</a></p><ul><li>Handshake syncing and querying fully working in the browser</li><li>Significant work has been done on the DHT communication as well as the related client libraries that are used for DHT and DNS</li><li>Redundancy/resiliency and connection retries/reconnecting were added to the different layers up to the HNS module itself</li><li>Has started researching and implementing IPFS</li><li>Started on a website rebranding and redesign via contracting</li></ul><h4>Sia Satellite</h4><p><a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/grant-proposal-sia-satellite/240/14">Link</a></p><ul><li>Contracts can now be formed using renterd and the satellite</li><li>Able to lock a part of the balance when a contract is formed and unlocking it when it ends</li><li>Made some web portal improvements and bug fixes</li><li>Next: contract renewals and further integration with renterd</li></ul><h3>Coming Next</h3><p>We encourage the community to provide their feedback and ask questions on the <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/">Sia Forum</a>! Community contribution and input is the best way to push proposals and projects to the next level.</p><p>You can see the list of all proposals <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/c/foundation/grants/">here</a>, and our proposal requirements <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/t/about-the-grants-category/">here</a>. See you next month!</p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=1e0d1cd9c74c" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/grants-program-update-march-2023-1e0d1cd9c74c">Grants Program Update, March 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Sia, March 2023]]></title>
            <link>https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-march-2023-6564463e35c0?source=rss----4cd2f4a04096---4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://medium.com/p/6564463e35c0</guid>
            <category><![CDATA[updates]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[siacoin]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[decentralization]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[cloud-storage]]></category>
            <category><![CDATA[ia]]></category>
            <dc:creator><![CDATA[Steve]]></dc:creator>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 15:22:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <atom:updated>2023-03-08T15:22:02.896Z</atom:updated>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*EzR6UZBxPS3rvOplNqqbew.png" /></figure><p>We’re back with the State of Sia, a monthly installment looking at development and team updates for The Sia Foundation.</p><p>As we head into the end of Q1, we’re moving towards an important time for the Foundation. Work on our new releases has been progressing steadily — and we’re rapidly approaching the point where we’ll have betas of our new software available. As a non-dev with a bit of technical know-how, it’s an absolute pleasure to be able to see the progress that is coming from our dev team. This is the stuff that will define the direction of Sia for the next few years, and we hope that you’ll love the work that we’ve done (and remember that they are betas 🙂).</p><p>The Grants Program has been moving along well, with a steady stream of proposals from grant-hopefuls as well as internal process improvements on our end to keep things running smoothly. We’ll expand more on those process improvements in the next grants blog post — I’ve even been considering a separate post talking about how we run things over there.</p><p>Next month you’ll likely see some very minor changes to our quarterly report, but we’ll call those out when they happen.</p><p>And that’s enough exposition, let’s take a look at our work this month.</p><h3>Development</h3><p>All public repos can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation">here</a>.</p><h3>renterd</h3><p>renterd will be our new stand-alone renter. The renterd repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd">here</a>, and the app is expected to be released in beta by the end of Q1.</p><ul><li>Fixed a deadlock in the worker (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/139">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed panics due to integer overflows (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/154">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed ongoing uploads failing when contracts renew midway through (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/161">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*nml05oo60EUkFk157cJM1A.png" /></figure><ul><li>Support for MySQL (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/148">Link</a>)</li><li>MaxCollateral and RemainingStorage now play into host scores (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/151">Link</a>)</li><li>Added some leeway before we start migrating data to avoid excessive repairs (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/165">Link</a>)</li><li>Correctly handled SIGTERM to allow for graceful shutdowns in docker (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/174">Link</a>)</li><li>Autopilot now keeps Ephemeral Accounts filled (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/167">Link</a>)</li><li>Default gouging settings are a bit stricter now (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/160">Link</a>)</li><li>Added runtime profiling (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/134">Link</a>)</li><li>Added allowlist (selecting a pool of hosts to form contracts with) (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/155">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*BKXAkiE_gAn8UckTSk3fcQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>Improved renter shutdown handling (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/129">Link</a>)</li><li>Improved session timeout handling (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/144">Link</a>)</li><li>Added a seed command to generate a new recovery phrase (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/renterd/pull/137">Link</a>)</li><li>Used ephemeral accounts for downloads</li><li>Extended documentation</li><li>Fixed a non-deterministic erasure coding bug which caused random panics</li></ul><h3>renterd UI</h3><iframe src="https://cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=https%3A%2F%2Fplayer.vimeo.com%2Fvideo%2F804445319%3Fh%3D944214daff%26app_id%3D122963&amp;dntp=1&amp;display_name=Vimeo&amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fvimeo.com%2F804445319&amp;image=https%3A%2F%2Fi.vimeocdn.com%2Fvideo%2F1623875576-8eeda72c8d02917295c2028dfffe19e64cbee537dd8556e5efad5780bd9dca55-d_1280&amp;key=a19fcc184b9711e1b4764040d3dc5c07&amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;schema=vimeo" width="1628" height="1080" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"><a href="https://medium.com/media/985e00fe1f083b9cc5ed94c742b876ef/href">https://medium.com/media/985e00fe1f083b9cc5ed94c742b876ef/href</a></iframe><ul><li>The contracts feature now shows a timeline visualization for active contracts</li><li>The contracts feature now shows and supports pagination and filtering active contracts.</li><li>Contracts are now filterable by expiry date.</li><li>Contracts are now filterable by renewal date.</li><li>The contracts filtering options are now accessible through the global cmd+k menu.</li><li>The Hosts feature now supports pagination and shows host info, scan, interaction, and uptime information.</li><li>The configuration page now includes the max storage price gouging setting.</li><li>The Autopilot settings were updated with the latest options including contract set.</li><li>The Files page now shows an onboarding/empty state when there are no files.</li></ul><h3>hostd</h3><p>hostd is the app you’ll be using to rent out your excess storage space to the Sia network.</p><ul><li>Added structured logging. Makes it easier to parse log events and determine the source of issues.</li><li>Migrated RHP3 to use the new volume and contract managers</li><li>Fixed wallet bugs causing transaction display issues</li><li>Added RenewedFrom field to contracts to make it possible to track contracts across renewals</li><li>Improved shutdown for all modules</li><li>Fixed issues with volume reloading and unavailable volumes.<br>docs</li></ul><h3>walletd</h3><p>walletd will be the place to store your Siacoins.</p><p>Ported to core/types instead of siad/types: (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/walletd/pull/11">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/walletd/pull/12">Link</a>), and (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/walletd/pull/13">Link</a>).</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*jtaMxe9v8cm0zmr02MBMGA.png" /></figure><h3>core</h3><p>The core repo is currently public and can be found <a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core">here</a>.</p><ul><li>Added RHP (renter-host protocol) packages to core. This allows renterd and hostd (and any other project) to share a single implementation of the RHP, rather than maintaining separate, possibly-incompatible versions (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/79">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*VvFZZZ48jkI9eGW9ekjsiQ.png" /></figure><ul><li>Fixed compatibility issues between core and siad. Lets hostd and renterd talk to siad (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/94">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/93">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/82">Link</a>), (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/81">Link</a>), and (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/80">Link</a>)</li><li>Implemented a blockchain manager and database in core. Previously, core had all of the bits and pieces required to perform Sia consensus, but it lacked an &quot;engine&quot; that could actually ingest blocks, apply the resulting state changes, and track the heaviest chain. This functionality was tested by successfully processing the full Sia blockchain (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/85">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed math for computing new collateral upon renew in core (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/83">Link</a>)</li><li>Fixed some encoding/decoding issues in the (refactored) rhpv3 protocol (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/94">Link</a>)</li><li>Added Source to delayed outputs. This makes it easier for wallets and explorers to display non-transactions like contract payouts (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/87">Link</a>)</li><li>Added support for testnet constants in core. This is a small but important change that allows core to be used on the testnet (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/96">Link</a>)</li><li>Added testnet tax Hardfork override. Enables hostd and renterd testnet builds (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/95">Link</a>)</li><li>Added some consensus tests after core was updated (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/core/pull/88">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>docs</h3><ul><li>Add linux setup guide for hosts (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/docs/pull/5">Link</a>)</li></ul><h3>jape</h3><p>jape is what we use to check that the API routes between client/server are consistent.</p><ul><li>Added support for strings in query parameters. Fixes API panics in hostd and renterd (<a href="https://github.com/SiaFoundation/jape/pull/10">Link</a>)</li></ul><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*yuy8JOrfy3uEi-OsMT6Lug.png" /></figure><h3>website</h3><ul><li>The website now loads fonts with zero layout shift, this optimization also applies to all other apps.</li><li>The website now shows the correct pronounciation of Sia at top of the homepage.</li><li>Code and content changes were made to the homepage to improve SEO and new user experience — the Grants program is now prominently featured on the homepage.</li><li>Migrate from nginx to caddy for serving website and other apps.</li></ul><h3>core UI libraries</h3><ul><li>ContractTimeline now shows the proof window.</li><li>ContractTimeline component is now aware of both block height and time units.</li><li>Added PaginatorKnownTotal and PagniatorUnknownTotal.</li><li>Fixed xxs Text size.</li><li>Added useClientFilters.</li><li>Button now has active and inactive variants.</li><li>The tailwind theme now supports text fill and shadow fill.</li><li>Fixed Button svg coloring.</li><li>Added useTableState.</li><li>Table component now has configurable empty and loading states.</li><li>Add base MenuItem components.</li><li>Added a max length of 200 characters to toast messages.</li><li>Added more block time conversion functions.</li><li>Added ConfigurationText, ConfigurationTipText.</li><li>Added HoverCard.</li><li>The TextField autofill coloring is now consistent across browsers.</li><li>AppSettings now has a password protected hooks mode.</li><li>Add useSettingsUpdate hook for PUT /settings.</li></ul><h3>Other Foundation Happenings</h3><h4>Advent of Code merch</h4><p>We’ve received the shirts for our Advent of Code participants! If you completed at least seven days during our December event, contact me at steve@sia.tech if you haven’t heard from me already.</p><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*YTFDFKm_U63bfzWlsH0VdQ.png" /></figure><h4>Grants Program</h4><p>The proposals continue! After approving Messari’s grant and recommending that Log Store re-apply at a later date, the committee recently reviewed another two, with a third and fourth on the docket for this week. The committee approved our biggest grant yet, and we’re incredibly excited to fill you with the latest update over at <a href="https://blog.sia.tech/">blog.sia.tech</a>.</p><p>Our Grants Program page on sia.tech was also updated to include a <a href="https://sia.tech/grants#grant-applicant-faq">Grantee FAQ</a> to answer some common questions that might come up during and after your grant proposal.</p><p>If you think you’ve got a great idea to benefit the Sia ecosystem, submit your proposal over at <a href="https://forum.sia.tech/">forum.sia.tech</a>.</p><h3>That’s all folks</h3><figure><img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/710/0*p8zPGQwXkEmdXD96.jpeg" /></figure><p>As we look towards the end of Q1 and the beginning of Q2, we can be proud of the quiet progress we’ve made. The growth of our grants program, the focus on scalability in our new apps, and the quality of both our team and community are all we need to continue driving to success.</p><p>Until next time!</p><p><a href="https://discord.gg/sia">Discord</a>, <a href="mailto:hello@sia.tech">Email</a></p><h3>Steve</h3><p>steve#4381 on Discord</p><img src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&referrerSource=full_rss&postId=6564463e35c0" width="1" height="1" alt=""><hr><p><a href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-state-of-sia-march-2023-6564463e35c0">The State of Sia, March 2023</a> was originally published in <a href="https://blog.sia.tech">The Sia Blog</a> on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>