<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Sia Foundation Newsroom</title>
        <link>sia.local</link>
        <description></description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 19:31:59 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Sia Foundation Newsroom</title>
            <url>sia.local/android-chrome-192x192.png</url>
            <link>sia.local</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2022, Sia Foundation</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia Welcomes New Non-Profit Foundation]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2021-foundation</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2021-foundation</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Stewardship of the decentralized storage protocol will be transferred to the Sia Foundation]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, the company building the Sia decentralized cloud storage network is evolving into two entities: the Sia Foundation, and Skynet Labs. Nebulous was previously responsible for both maintaining core Sia protocol infrastructure as well as building layer two and applications atop that infrastructure. The Foundation will dedicate itself entirely to the core Sia software and its ecosystem, while Skynet Labs will focus its resources on developing Skynet, an application development and hosting platform backed by the Sia network.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Since 2015, users of the Sia storage platform have stored over 8 PB of data across its distributed network of hosts. By harnessing the power of consumer-grade hardware in aggregate, Sia can achieve transfer speeds in excess of 1 gigabit per second, at one tenth or even one hundredth the cost of traditional centralized providers. Usage of the platform doubled in 2020, following the launch of Skynet and the increasing adoption of third-party applications built on Sia, including StoreWise, Filebase, Arzen, Pixeldrain, and more. Bolstering these two channels of rapid growth underlies Nebulous&#x27; evolution into Sia Foundation and Skynet Labs.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">&quot;Sia is public infrastructure,&quot; said Luke Champine—formerly a Co-founder of Nebulous, now President of the Sia Foundation. &quot;The network has matured to the point where it no longer makes sense for its development to be managed by a for-profit entity. It&#x27;s time to hand the reins over to a neutral, non-profit organization that can ensure Sia&#x27;s stability and longevity. I am honored to be entrusted with the duty of leading that organization.&quot;</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">David Vorick, CEO of Skynet Labs (formerly Nebulous), says this will enable Skynet Labs to capitalize on the platform&#x27;s recent growth. “There has always been a tension in the Sia ecosystem between what the community needs and what the for-profit entity needs. Now that there is a nonprofit foundation that is solely accountable to the community, everyone will be better positioned to thrive.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">The Sia Foundation is funded by a subsidy of Siacoins, added to the blockchain by a &quot;hardfork&quot; software update that activated last night. The update was adopted by a majority of the network&#x27;s users, many of whom expressed public support for the move. According to community member and contributor, SiaStats, the Sia Foundation “adds value and benefits every actor on the network. It safeguards the mission of Sia and enables grants, new developers, marketing, and growth actions.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">In keeping with its commitment to improving the Sia network, in 2021 the Foundation plans to undertake a substantial overhaul of the Sia consensus algorithm, allowing the software to be used on smartphones and other low-power devices and enabling more users to fully validate the Sia blockchain. As for Skynet Labs, the company aims to replace modern web infrastructure with a decentralized upgrade which allows users to have control over their data and allows developers to innovate more rapidly.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About the Sia Foundation</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">The Sia Foundation is a non-profit corporation that maintains, improves, and promotes the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia</a> distributed storage network. It was founded in 2020 and is funded by a perpetual subsidy built into the Sia protocol. All code, research, educational materials, and other products of the Foundation&#x27;s work will be made available to the public free of charge and under open-source licenses.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Skynet Labs</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css"><a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet Labs</a>, formerly known as Nebulous, builds uncompromising software infrastructure for the decentralized internet and is the team responsible for Skynet. Skynet is an application development and hosting platform and storage on Skynet is provided by Sia, the leading decentralized cloud storage network.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet Labs defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most importantly – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Skynet Labs stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently delivers real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is funded by Paradigm, Bain Capital Ventures, A.Capital, Bessemer Venture Partners, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Skynet Announces SkyDB, Unlocking a Fully Decentralized Internet]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2020-skydb</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2020-skydb</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[SkyDB enables decentralized social media to take on `The Social Dilemma`]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet Labs, the company building the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia</a> decentralized cloud storage platform and the <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet</a> application hosting platform, today announced the launch of SkyDB, a framework that allows developers to build feature-complete applications that compete with the likes of Youtube, Twitter, Instagram, and Tiktok.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">The fabric of our society and the way we interact with each other has been heavily influenced and altered by the rise of social media platforms. Biased algorithms amplify stereotypes, constant streams of content compete for our attention, and manipulated narratives wedge digital divides across political ideologies and cultural identities. As pertinently pointed out by the popular Social Dilemma documentary, “We have moved from a tools-based technology environment to an addiction and manipulation based technology environment&quot;</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">SkyDB enables developers to realize the full potential of a <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-war-for-a-free-internet-c0a7fcc00c46" class="c-gjiLXk">Free Internet</a>. Building these Web3 applications not only has benefits of privacy and control over one’s data but it ushers innovation currently impossible in the siloed centralized web of today. SkyDB is a framework that allows users to create decentralized accounts and store mutable data in those accounts which can be accessed globally from any device. The user does not need to sync any blockchains or run any special software — a normal web browser is sufficient. For more details on the inner workings of SkyDB and the potential it unlocks, check out our latest <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/skydb-a-mutable-database-for-the-decentralized-web-7170beeaa985" class="c-gjiLXk">blog post</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“Today is a turning point in history where the decentralized web starts to eat the centralized web,” said David Vorick, Skynet Labs CEO and lead developer. “Skynet gives developers more tools to create better experiences for users. Skynet in many senses is the first true cloud, where all data is available everywhere, regardless of the original application.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet was <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/skynet-bdf0209d6d34" class="c-gjiLXk">launched</a> back in February 2020 and since then has seen accelerated growth in developer interest and usage. Users around the world have uploaded more than 2.5 million files amounting to 15+ TeraBytes of data using Skynet. In October, Skynet crossed a record-high of 150,000 downloads in a single day.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">A thriving community of developers has built over 150 applications in the span of a few months including a Video Streaming app <a target="_blank" href="https://skylive.coolhd.hu/" class="c-gjiLXk">SkyLive</a>, Blogging apps like <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/hns/wakio" class="c-gjiLXk">Wakio</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/DADAgjHeqGnQ1hIEET54YyIZhBN_oz51HMogZsLiS60KTA/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skyblog Builder</a>, Video &amp; Image gallery app <a target="_blank" href="https://skygallery.xyz/" class="c-gjiLXk">SkyGallery</a>, a Decentralized AppStore <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/redsolver/skydroid" class="c-gjiLXk">Skydroid</a>. The full list of Skynet Apps can be explored at the <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/hns/skyapps/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet AppStore</a>, and an English language <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/_BmN2WhKvKAm0CzsfmHyiP81yUnYyQxh5To8JkVbj1RUxg/www/index.html" class="c-gjiLXk">Wikipedia clone</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“Next-generation applications are already being built on Skynet with more developers joining the community every day,” said Manasi Vora, Skynet Labs’ VP Strategy &amp; Operations. “Skynet shines in how its easy to use not just for developers but also for the end-users, a rarity in the blockchain space.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">By building on the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia network</a>, Skynet delivers a 10x reduction in storage costs and a 100x reduction in bandwidth costs when compared to centralized providers, without sacrificing performance or reliability. Skynet achieves 1 gigabit per second in download and uploads speeds, with more improvements coming in future releases.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Interested in Skynet? Learn more at <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Siasky.net</a>, join us on <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/sia" class="c-gjiLXk">Discord</a>, and email us at <a target="_blank" href="mailto:hello@sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">hello@sia.tech</a>.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Skynet Labs</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet Labs, previously known as Nebulous, builds uncompromising software infrastructure for the decentralized internet. This includes <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia</a>, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, and <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet</a>, a content and application hosting platform.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet Labs defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most important – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Skynet Labs stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently deliver real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is headquartered in Boston. It is funded by Paradigm, Bain Capital Ventures, A.Capital, Bessemer Venture Partners, Dragonfly Capital Partners, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia Announces $3M Seed Round to Accelerate Development and Adoption of the Web3 platform Skynet]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2020-funding</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2020-funding</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Paradigm leads the round of financing; Nebulous to solely focus on Skynet]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, the company building the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia</a> decentralized cloud storage platform and the <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet</a> application hosting platform, today announced it has closed a $3M funding round led by Paradigm with participation from Bain Capital Ventures, Bessemer Venture Partners, A.Capital, Collaborative Fund, Dragonfly Capital Partners, Hack VC, INBlockchain, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors. The round will help the company scale and accelerate the development and adoption of Skynet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Today’s internet monopolized by tech giants struggles with fundamental challenges in privacy, reliability, and has excessive control over our data and the way we interact with the world. Skynet enables high speed, low cost, and superior infrastructure to serve as the storage foundation for <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-war-for-a-free-internet-c0a7fcc00c46" class="c-gjiLXk">a free Internet</a>. Where data is globally accessible, user-controlled, censorship-resistant, and not fragmented in walled gardens.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet empowers developers to deploy applications to a decentralized network in just minutes and be immediately available to everyone across the world. Importantly, end-users can directly access content on Skynet without needing to run full nodes or deal with cryptocurrencies. It paves the path for more powerful applications, more dynamic user experiences, and disintermediates the web to ensure that publishers and creators are paid the full amount that they deserve. Skynet enables the decentralized web ecosystem to realize the full potential of a free internet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“The possibilities created by Skynet blow our minds. The project has enabled a growing ecosystem of builders to quickly prototype censorship-resistant applications and interactive websites including interfaces to Ethereum smart contracts like Uniswap,” said Dan Robinson, Research Partner at Paradigm. “We’re investing in the Skynet team because we believe they have the right combination of talent, experience, and community to shepherd us into the era of the Decentralized Web.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/skynet-bdf0209d6d34" class="c-gjiLXk">launched</a> the Skynet platform back in February 2020 and since then has seen accelerated growth in developer interest and usage. More than 1.6 million files have been uploaded and shared amounting to 10+ TB of data using Skynet. A thriving community of developers has built over 100 applications in the span of a few months including a Video Streaming app <a target="_blank" href="https://skylive.coolhd.hu/" class="c-gjiLXk">SkyLive</a>, Blogging apps like <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/hns/wakio" class="c-gjiLXk">Wakio</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/DADAgjHeqGnQ1hIEET54YyIZhBN_oz51HMogZsLiS60KTA/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skyblog Builder</a>, Video &amp; Image gallery app <a target="_blank" href="https://skygallery.xyz/" class="c-gjiLXk">SkyGallery</a>, and a Decentralized AppStore <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/redsolver/skydroid" class="c-gjiLXk">Skydroid</a>. The full list of Skynet Apps can be explored at the <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/hns/skyapps/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet AppStore</a>. We believe the next generation of Twitter, Medium, TikTok will be built on Skynet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">By building on the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia network</a>, Skynet delivers a 10x reduction in storage costs and a 100x reduction in bandwidth costs when compared to centralized providers, without sacrificing performance or reliability. Skynet achieves 1 gigabit per second in download and uploads speeds, with more improvements coming in future releases.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“For the first time, the decentralized web feels within reach. We’re not talking about a web that is technically feasible yet crippled compared to the centralized alternatives, we are talking about a decentralized web that will become an unstoppable force” said David Vorick, Nebulous CEO and Skynet Lead Developer. “Ten years from now, using centralized applications instead of decentralized applications will feel like using a fax machine instead of email.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">In addition to the funding news, Nebulous is announcing its <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/skynet-the-future-of-nebulous-c9922eb53456" class="c-gjiLXk">rebranding</a> to Skynet to solely focused on developing and growing the Skynet ecosystem. Next-generation applications are already being built on Skynet with more developers joining the community every day. Skynet is different from any platform or technology than has ever been built before. Because of that, we are thrilled to be doubling down on what we know will become the future of the Internet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Interested in Skynet? Learn more at <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">siasky.net</a>, join us on <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/sia" class="c-gjiLXk">Discord</a>, or email us at <a target="_blank" href="mailto:hello@sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">hello@sia.tech</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Want to help us re-decentralize the Internet? Nebulous is hiring for positions in marketing and developer evangelism. Learn more about our projects and <a target="_blank" href="https://jobs.lever.co/SkynetLabs" class="c-gjiLXk">apply today</a>!</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Nebulous</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous builds uncompromising software infrastructure for the decentralized internet. This includes <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia</a>, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, and <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet</a>, a content and application hosting platform.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most important – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Nebulous stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently deliver real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is headquartered in Boston. Before the round led by Paradigm, Nebulous was funded by Bain Capital Ventures, A.Capital, Bessemer Venture Partners, Dragonfly Capital Partners, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Paradigm</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.paradigm.xyz/" class="c-gjiLXk">Paradigm</a> is a crypto-focused investment firm based in San Francisco founded by Fred Ehrsam and Matt Huang. The firm makes investments focusing on crypto and blockchain technologies from the earliest stages of ideation through maturity. Prior to founding Paradigm, Fred co-founded Coinbase, the largest cryptocurrency company in the US, and Matt was a partner at Sequoia Capital focusing on early-stage venture investments including leading the firm’s cryptocurrency efforts.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia Announces Skynet, the Storage Foundation for a Free Internet]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2020-skynet</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2020-skynet</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Skynet is available with Sia version 1.4.3 and ready to use today!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, the company building the Sia decentralized cloud storage network, today <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/skynet-bdf0209d6d34" class="c-gjiLXk">announced</a> the launch of <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Skynet</a>, a decentralized CDN and file sharing platform for application developers. Skynet enables high speed, low cost, and superior infrastructure to serve as the storage foundation for a free Internet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Today’s decentralized applications (dapps) largely rely on centralized data storage providers like Amazon, due to the lack of reliable, fast, and production-ready decentralized alternatives. This makes it difficult for developers to build truly decentralized applications and prevents the dapp ecosystem from realizing the real potential of a <a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-war-for-a-free-internet-c0a7fcc00c46" class="c-gjiLXk">Free Internet</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Skynet provides an easy-to-use data storage and publishing mechanism on which developers can build decentralized applications. With a simple API and SDKs for popular programming languages, Skynet empowers developers to easily integrate decentralized storage into their applications. Importantly, end-users can directly access files on Skynet without needing to run full nodes or deal with cryptocurrencies.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">By building on the <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia Network</a>, Skynet delivers a 10x reduction in storage costs and a 100x reduction in bandwidth costs when compared to centralized providers, without sacrificing performance or reliability. Amazingly, Skynet achieves 1 gigabit per second in download and uploads speeds, with more improvements coming in future releases.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“After seven years of nonstop work, applications built on decentralized storage are finally viable. I can say without a doubt that Skynet is the most powerful tech we&#x27;ve ever built” said David Vorick, Nebulous CEO and Sia Lead Developer. “Skynet makes it possible for content and applications to be deployed to a decentralized network just in seconds and be immediately available to everyone across the world.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Our vision for Skynet involves supporting decentralized content publishing. Whether through news articles, blog posts, music, or video, Nebulous envisions Skynet as a decentralized and censorship-resistant foundation for content creators to deliver media their audience cares about. No more de-platforming, no more exploitation.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“One place where Skynet shines is speed. Page loading is almost instant. Deployment to Skynet is also almost instant. We’ve demonstrated that decentralized storage can be as fast as its centralized competitors” said Manasi Vora, Nebulous’ Head of Product Strategy. “With storage and bandwidth prices so low, we expect Skynet to enable previously unimaginable applications and spark a renaissance in media-heavy applications.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Since Sia’s launch in 2015, users have stored over 4 PB of data across over 1 million storage smart contracts. Currently, the Sia network has 2.2 PB of available storage capacity and Sia software has been downloaded over 1 million times. Sia has a thriving community of third-party developers who have launched file sharing websites like <a target="_blank" href="https://pixeldrain.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">PixelDrain</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://storewise.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Storewise</a>, cloud offerings like <a target="_blank" href="https://filebase.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">Filebase</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://arzen.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Arzen</a>, and companion apps like <a target="_blank" href="https://keops.cc/decentralizer" class="c-gjiLXk">Decentralizer</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://siacentral.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">SiaCentral</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Interested in Skynet? Learn more at <a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">siasky.net</a> join us on <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/sia" class="c-gjiLXk">Discord</a>, and email us at <a target="_blank" href="mailto:hello@sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">hello@sia.tech</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Want to help us re-decentralize the Internet? Nebulous is hiring for positions in engineering and operations. Learn more about our projects and <a target="_blank" href="https://jobs.lever.co/SkynetLabs" class="c-gjiLXk">apply today</a>!</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Nebulous</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css"><a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Nebulous</a> builds uncompromising blockchain hardware and software infrastructure for the decentralized internet. This includes Sia, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, and Obelisk, a producer of blockchain-related hardware.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most important – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Nebulous stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently delivers real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is headquartered in Boston. Nebulous is funded by Bain Capital Ventures, A.Capital, Raptor Group, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nebulous Enters into Settlement with SEC Regarding 2014 Offering of Sianotes and 2015 Conversion into Siafunds]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2019-settlement</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2019-settlement</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The SEC takes no enforcement action with respect to Siacoins or current activity on the Sia network]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, the company building the Sia decentralized cloud storage network, announced today that it has entered into a settlement with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC). Without admitting or denying liability, Nebulous settled an SEC claim relating to the unregistered May 2014 offer and sale of Sianotes and the June 2015 conversion of Sianotes into Siafunds. As reflected in the settled order, the SEC did not take any enforcement action with respect to the Siacoin token or any current activity on the Sia network, and the order does not require Nebulous to register the Siacoin token as a security with the SEC.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">The Sia network has employed a <strong>two-token model</strong> since its 2014 whitepaper and 2015 launch; Siacoins are used to buy and sell cloud storage space while Siafund investors receive a small share of total storage revenue. This two-token model creates an ideal ecosystem, focusing Siafund investors and the Nebulous team on product development and long-term network growth. Today, users are storing over 500 terabytes of data on the Sia network.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">In May 2014, Nebulous conducted a $120,000 offering of a token called Sianotes, which were converted to Siafunds upon network launch in 2015. The offering took place through Bitcointalk.org, three months before the Ethereum offering. During these earliest stages of development of blockchain technologies, the Nebulous team did not anticipate that the SEC might later deem Sianotes or any other blockchain assets to be securities.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">In April 2018, Nebulous conducted a new offering of Siafunds. By then, however, the SEC had issued its 2017 <a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/investreport/34-81207.pdf" class="c-gjiLXk">DAO Report</a> and the SEC Chairman and SEC staff’s public statements signaled a shift in regulatory focus that caused Nebulous to understand that the SEC might consider Siafunds to be securities. Armed with this knowledge, Nebulous engaged sophisticated securities counsel and completed a $1.5M Regulation D offering of Siafunds that it called a Tokenized Securities Offering (TSO). The TSO properly complied with all requirements for such an offering.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Shortly after the close of the April 2018 offering, Nebulous was contacted by the SEC which had initiated an investigation concerning Nebulous and the Sia network. Over the course of the SEC’s investigation, Nebulous cooperated fully and provided documents and information about the company, its offerings, and the general Sia network (including the role of Siacoins and Siafunds).</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Upon completion of its investigation, and as reflected in the settled order, the SEC concluded that because Siafunds were securities, the failure to register the 2014 offering and 2015 conversion constituted violations of Section 5 of the Securities Act of 1933. Without admitting to or denying the SEC’s allegations, Nebulous agreed to a settlement and will pay disgorgement of $120,000, prejudgment interest of $24,601.85, and a civil money penalty of $80,000, for a total of approximately $225,000.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Zach Herbert, Nebulous Chief Operating Officer, stated, “Given that Nebulous had properly registered its 2018 offering of Siafunds in the wake of the SEC’s 2017 guidance regarding digital assets, we were disappointed that the SEC chose to take action with respect to the relatively small offering conducted years before we had the benefit of that guidance. However, beyond that, we are pleased at how the company and the network fared under such intense regulatory scrutiny and that after a thorough investigation, the SEC asserted no claims regarding Siacoins or the current operations on the Sia network.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">David Vorick, Nebulous Cofounder and Chief Executive Officer, added, “From the earliest days of building Sia, we have always emphasized the importance of ethics and have constantly strived to safeguard user freedoms. As we continue to build the Sia network, we will continue to uphold these values and work towards building a better world that empowers individuals.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Questions or comments? Feel free to reach out to the Sia team at <a target="_blank" href="mailto:hello@sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">hello@sia.tech</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Notable Information About Siacoins</p><ul><li>Siacoins were never used for fundraising.</li><li>Siacoins are mined via Proof-of-Work.</li><li>Nebulous pre-mined less than 0.1% of the total Siacoin supply at launch.</li><li>Nebulous currently holds less than 0.1% of the total Siacoin supply.</li><li>Nebulous does not actively mine any Siacoins.</li></ul><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Helpful Links</p><ul><li><a target="_blank" href="https://support.sia.tech/category/jukn3w66fk-sec-settlement" class="c-gjiLXk">Settlement FAQs</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="https://blog.sia.tech/the-ico-paradox-and-how-to-fix-it-3bfc61bc6eb8" class="c-gjiLXk">Blog Post about Sia’s Two-Token Model</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/litigation/admin/2019/33-10715.pdf" class="c-gjiLXk">SEC Settlement</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/enforce/33-10715-s" class="c-gjiLXk">SEC Administrative Summary</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/rules/other/2019/33-10716.pdf" class="c-gjiLXk">SEC Waiver</a></li><li><a target="_blank" href="https://www.sec.gov/divisions/corpfin/cf-noaction/2019/nebulous-093019-506.pdf" class="c-gjiLXk">Waiver Request Letter</a></li></ul><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">About Nebulous
<a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Nebulous</a> builds uncompromising blockchain hardware and software infrastructure for the decentralized internet. This includes Sia, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, and Obelisk, the USA&#x27;s leading ASIC mining hardware producer.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most important – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Nebulous stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently delivers real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is headquartered in Boston. Nebulous is funded by Bain Capital Ventures, Raptor Group, First Star Ventures, and other notable investors.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia Announces $3.25M Seed Round to Accelerate Development of the Sia Decentralized Cloud Storage Platform]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2019-funding</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2019-funding</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Bain Capital Ventures leads the round of financing; Sia announces landmark v1.4.1 release]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, the company building the Sia decentralized cloud storage platform, today announced it has closed a $3.25M funding round led by Bain Capital Ventures with participation from Bessemer Venture Partners, A.Capital, Collaborative Fund, Dragonfly Capital Partners, Hack VC, INBlockchain, SV Angel, and other notable investors. The round will help the company scale and accelerate the development and adoption of Sia.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Today’s cloud storage industry, monopolized by tech giants, struggles with fundamental challenges in price, privacy, and reliability. Sia, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, leverages blockchain technology to create a data storage marketplace that is more robust and more affordable than traditional cloud storage providers. Data storage on Sia currently costs about $1 per TB per month – an order of magnitude cheaper than Amazon S3 – and provides users with true privacy and control over their data.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“Just as all conventional apps need conventional storage, decentralized apps need decentralized storage, which makes decentralized storage a core foundation of decentralized finance and the decentralized web,” said Salil Deshpande, partner at Bain Capital Ventures. “Sia is in production today, without architectural issues, and without reliance on yet-to-come fundamental technical breakthroughs.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Since company inception, users of the platform have already stored over 4 PB of data across 925,000 storage smart contracts. The Sia network currently has 2 PB of available storage capacity and Sia software has been downloaded over 1 million times. Nebulous has also fostered a thriving community of third-party developers. These contributors have launched file sharing websites like <a target="_blank" href="https://pixeldrain.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">PixelDrain</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://goobox.io/" class="c-gjiLXk">Goobox</a>, cloud offerings like <a target="_blank" href="https://filebase.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">Filebase</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://sia-cloud.tech/" class="c-gjiLXk">Sia-Cloud</a>, and companion apps like <a target="_blank" href="https://keops.cc/decentralizer" class="c-gjiLXk">Decentralizer</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://siacentral.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">SiaCentral</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“The Sia developer community has seen massive growth in the past 3 months, including the addition of both consumer-facing and enterprise-facing startups that use Sia to power their applications,” said David Vorick, Nebulous CEO. “These companies have brought substantial adoption and diversification to the Sia ecosystem, and are demonstrating that Sia is making a difference today in the lives of consumers and businesses.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">In addition to the funding news, Nebulous just released v1.4.1, making Sia production-ready for storage. Version 1.4.1 adds seed-based file recovery, allowing users to backup and restore their files on a new computer using just their 29-word seed. Combined with massively increased scalability to 20 TB per uploader, Sia is now competitive with traditional cloud storage providers. Features slated for release later this year include blazing-fast video streaming, integrations with popular applications, and early CDN capabilities.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Interested in Sia for personal or business use? <a target="_blank" href="https://sia.tech/get-started" class="c-gjiLXk">Download today</a> and contact us via <a target="_blank" href="https://discord.gg/sia" class="c-gjiLXk">Discord</a> or email at <a target="_blank" href="mailto:hello@sia.tech" class="c-gjiLXk">hello@sia.tech</a>.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Want to help us re-decentralize the Internet? Nebulous is hiring for positions in engineering and operations. Learn more about our projects and <a target="_blank" href="https://jobs.lever.co/SkynetLabs" class="c-gjiLXk">apply today</a>!</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Nebulous</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css"><a target="_blank" href="https://siasky.net/" class="c-gjiLXk">Nebulous</a> builds uncompromising blockchain hardware and software infrastructure for the decentralized internet. This includes Sia, the leading decentralized cloud storage platform, and Obelisk, the USA&#x27;s leading ASIC mining hardware producer.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous defines uncompromising infrastructure as scalable, trustless, secure, and – most important – fully decentralized. In a blockchain industry filled with hype but lacking substance, Nebulous stands out as one of the few deeply technical teams that consistently delivers real products with significant potential.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous, Inc. was founded in 2014 and is headquartered in Boston. Prior to the round led by Bain Capital Ventures, Nebulous was funded by Raptor Group, First Star Ventures, Fenbushi Capital, and INBlockchain.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Bain Capital Ventures</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css"><a target="_blank" href="https://www.baincapitalventures.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">Bain Capital Ventures</a> partners with disruptive founders to accelerate their ideas to market. The firm invests from seed to growth in startups driving transformation across industries, from security and cloud infrastructure to logistics and e-commerce to finance and healthcare. The firm has helped launch and commercialize more than 240 companies, including DocuSign, Jet.com, Kiva Systems, Lime, LinkedIn, Rapid7, Redis Labs, Rent the Runway, Rubrik, SendGrid, and SurveyMonkey. Bain Capital Ventures has $5.2 billion in assets under management with offices in San Francisco, New York, Boston and Palo Alto. Follow the firm via <a target="_blank" href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/bain-capital-ventures/" class="c-gjiLXk">LinkedIn</a> or <a target="_blank" href="https://twitter.com/BainCapVC" class="c-gjiLXk">Twitter</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia receives $400k grant from INBlockchain for development of its cloud storage platform]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2017-grant</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2017-grant</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Nebulous today has received a $400,000 grant from INBlockchain for Sia development]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous today has received a $400,000 grant from <a target="_blank" href="http://inblockchain.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">INBlockchain</a> for Sia development. The Sia network has grown rapidly in 2017, and now consists of almost 1000 hosts across the world offering a collective 3+ PB of storage capacity. INBlockchain’s grant will allow Nebulous to focus on building Sia into the storage layer of the internet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">“We are thrilled to receive INBlockchain’s generous grant and look forward to continuing Sia development,” said David Vorick, cofounder and CEO of Nebulous. “This grant means Sia does not need to focus on fundraising, and can focus entirely on delivering strong technology.”</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Sia is a decentralized data storage platform that connects renters seeking cloud storage to a worldwide network of hosts offering storage capacity. Hosts and renters form storage smart-contracts that are stored on the Sia blockchain. Sia splits apart and encrypts all files, ensuring privacy and security. By creating a marketplace where thousands of hosts bid on storage contracts, costs are far lower than traditional cloud providers. Ultimately, Sia aims to be the backbone storage layer of the internet.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">INBlockchain provided the grant so that the Sia team can focus on development and not on fundraising. &quot;Don&#x27;t worry about money, just have things well done,” said Li Xiaolai, founder of INBlockchain.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Sia will release v1.3.0 this week, and will introduce features like file sharing over the coming months.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">About Nebulous
Nebulous, Inc. is the parent company to Sia. Currently a team of four, Nebulous’ focus is reliable, decentralized infrastructure to help bring forward the future. Sia is currently the primary project of the Nebulous team.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">About INBlockchain
INBlockchain is a China-based firm founded by Li Xiaolai that invests in what they call Meaningful Blockchain Applications, or MBAcoins. Learn more about their investment philosophy <a target="_blank" href="https://github.com/xiaolai/INB-Principles/" class="c-gjiLXk">here</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sia Startup raises $750k seed round to further blockchain-powered, distributed storage platform]]></title>
            <link>sia.local/newsroom/2016-funding</link>
            <guid>sia.local/newsroom/2016-funding</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[After 1.0 release, Nebulous targets enterprise expansion]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous today has raised $750,000 for Sia, led by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.procyonventures.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">Procyon Ventures</a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.raptorgroup.com/" class="c-gjiLXk">Raptor Group</a>, with participation from <a target="_blank" href="https://www.fenbushicapital.vc/index_en.html" class="c-gjiLXk">Fenbushi Capital</a> and angel investor Xiaolai Li. To date, Nebulous has raised $1.25M in total funding. Sia achieved its 1.0 release in June of this year and the funding will allow the team to accelerate its development and further its use by enterprises.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Sia is a collaborative data storage platform which allows users to store and retrieve large amounts of data quickly and securely. Smart contracts allow users to seamlessly acquire storage from hosts all over the world which have agreed to rent space on their hard drives. Sia’s blockchain-based technology ensure hosts aren’t able to see inside the data they store while guaranteeing the data is available when needed. By creating a marketplace where thousands of hosts bid on a storage contract, this allows the platform to be more reliable and also deliver significant cost savings compared to traditional cloud providers.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">&quot;By using encryption, cryptographic contracts, and redundancy, Sia enables a collection of untrusted and unknown machines to be combined into a single logical cloud storage host that is faster, cheaper, and more reliable than traditional cloud storage platforms.&quot; David Vorick, cofounder and CEO, said.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Since inception in 2014, Sia’s focus has always been on bringing strong, fully decentralized cloud storage to the world. The first fully decentralized prototype of Sia launched in June 2015, a cloud storage platform that allowed both hosts and renters to participate in a network that had no centralized services or single points of failure. The following year was spent iterating on the tech, focusing on scalability and on an easy-to-use third party API. June 2016 saw the release of the completed API, along with a compatibility promise that all programs and services built using the 1.0.0 API would continue to work with all future versions of Sia.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">With its 1.0 release, Sia became the first full-decentralized marketplace for cloud storage to move into production. Moving forward, the company’s primary focus will be on growing the developer community and beginning expansion into the enterprise market. Storage device maker Minebox has announced their forthcoming Minebox NAS will integrate with the platform to allow users to take full advantage of Sia for both storing data as well as renting space onto the network.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">&quot;Every team that works with data in a meaningful way, from AI to precision medicine to Industrial IoT, is seeing an explosion in the size of the datasets they want to be able to work with. Sia has the potential to be a game changer for them by fundamentally changing how data is captured, stored, and distributed.&quot; said Procyon partner Drew Volpe.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">&quot;We are impressed by Sia&#x27;s distributed cloud storage platform, the community of engaged users, and see an opportunity for Sia to disrupt centralized cloud storage providers with improved security and rationalized storage expense.&quot; said Raptor Associate Director Joshua Langsam.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Nebulous</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Nebulous is the parent company to Sia. Currently a team of four, Nebulous’ focus is reliable, decentralized infrastructure to help bring forward the future. Sia is currently the primarily project of the Nebulous team.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Procyon</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Procyon Ventures is an early-stage, venture capital firm based in Boston, MA. Procyon partners with entrepreneurs solving real-world problems using data and machine intelligence, focusing on applications of frontier technologies such as AI, computational biotech, connected sensors, AR/VR, and industrial IoT. We believe in investing with conviction in visionary founders with deep technical experience. Drawing on our network of strategic partners across industries and regions, we help startups think big and grow fast.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Raptor Group</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Raptor Group Holdings is a private investment company backed by the Family Office of Jim Pallotta. Mr. Pallotta has been a professional and personal investor for over 30 years. Raptor Group&#x27;s culture is relentlessly entrepreneurial, opportunistic, flexible, and nimble; these values comprise the Firm&#x27;s core DNA and manifest across every aspect of our business. We source and invest in companies across various stages and asset classes, ranging from early stage venture to both private and public equity. Our key investment criteria is the opportunity to leverage the team&#x27;s operating and strategic expertise and extensive global network to add value and drive results.</p><h1 class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-gHgbiV-size-4 c-dgLzyK-bqAxbP-size-5 c-dgLzyK-iciggwu-css">About Fenbushi</h1><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">Founded in 2015, Fenbushi Capital is the first China-based venture capital firm that exclusively invests in Blockchain-enabled companies. Our mission is to accelerate the inevitable future of Blockchain economy by supporting as many companies as possible.</p><p class="c-dgLzyK c-dgLzyK-iMVRpC-size-3 c-dgLzyK-htKPem-size-4 c-dgLzyK-ibrHugz-css">We strongly believe Blockchain technology will play an important role bringing much more transparency, efficiency, and robustness into the global economy. With our experienced partners in both traditional finance and the blockchain technology and many startup companies, we hope to bring this vision into fruition.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>hello@sia.tech (Sia Foundation)</author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>